<table-wrap xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="tbl2" position="float"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.02009.020</object-id><label>Table 2.</label><caption><p>Simulated intra-Golgi transport of albumin mediated by vesicles, predicts extremely fast turnover of cisternal rims</p><p><bold>DOI:</bold> <ext-link ext-link-type="doi" xlink:href="10.7554/eLife.02009.020">http://dx.doi.org/10.7554/eLife.02009.020</ext-link></p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><tbody><tr><td>Vesicle diameter (nm)</td><td align="char" char="." colspan="2">50</td><td align="char" char="." colspan="2">60</td><td align="char" char="." colspan="2">70</td></tr><tr><td>Number of cisternae</td><td align="char" char=".">4</td><td align="char" char=".">6</td><td align="char" char=".">4</td><td align="char" char=".">6</td><td align="char" char=".">4</td><td align="char" char=".">6</td></tr><tr><td>Steps for 90% equilibration</td><td align="char" char=".">19,617</td><td align="char" char=".">44,230</td><td align="char" char=".">11,352</td><td align="char" char=".">25,595</td><td align="char" char=".">7149</td><td align="char" char=".">16,120</td></tr><tr><td>Rim turnover time (s)</td><td align="char" char=".">0.576</td><td align="char" char=".">0.255</td><td align="char" char=".">0.829</td><td align="char" char=".">0.368</td><td align="char" char=".">1.129</td><td align="char" char=".">0.500</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn><p>The size and geometry of the Golgi stack and vesicles used for the simulations are defined in the legend to <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig6s1">Figure 6&#8212;figure supplement 1</xref>. The variable parameters used for the simulation are: diameter of vesicles (from 50 to 70 nm) and number of cisternae (between 4 and 6). Albumin transport is considered to proceed stepwise, where each step is defined as one vesicle detaching from each cisterna and fusing with an adjacent one. For the calculations presented here, the albumin concentration in the vesicles is considered to be 20% of that present in the cisterna (see <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig5">Figure 5</xref> and also legend to <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig6s1">Figure 6&#8212;figure supplement 1</xref>). The number of steps required to achieve 90% equilibration of albumin across the stack was computed and the time required for a single turnover event of the cisternal rim (rim turnover time) was calculated as described in the legend to <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig6s1">Figure 6&#8212;figure supplement 1</xref>. The rim turnover time varied from 0.25 to 1.12 s or in other words, the rim turns over from 4 to 1 times per second, depending on the condition used for the simulation. The results presented here are for the scenario 'a' (discussed in <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig6s1">Figure 6&#8212;figure supplement 1</xref>) and the results are very similar even in the case of scenario 'b'.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap>