<table-wrap xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="app1table2" position="float"><label>Appendix 1&#8212;table 2.</label><caption><title>Crosslink-detachment vs domain unfolding.</title><p>A summary of different scenario and their expected mechanical response.</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th/><th>Model</th><th>Strain-softening of steady state moduli</th><th>Solid-like steady state</th><th>Peak in relaxation time vs strain</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>i</td><td>Randomly crosslinked semiflexible polymer gel (Refs [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib10">Broedersz and MacKintosh, 2014</xref>])</td><td>Initial entropic stiffening and subsequent softening due to force dependent crosslink detachment. Crosslink unbinding causes energy dissipation and stress relaxation.</td><td>Solid-like in stiffening regime and fluid-like in softening regime.</td><td>No</td></tr><tr><td>ii</td><td>Aligned microtubules with force dependent crosslinks (Refs [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib2">Ahmadzadeh et al., 2015</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib14">de Rooij and Kuhl, 2018</xref>])</td><td>Can exhibit direct softening due to crosslink detachment as entropic effect is minimal.</td><td>Fluid-like at long times unless one invokes another parallel structure with permanent crosslinks.</td><td>No</td></tr><tr><td>iii</td><td>Force dependent unfolding and force dependent re-folding of spectrin domains.</td><td>Exhibits direct strain softening when spectrin is in fully extended configuration (as suggested by 190 nm tetramer spacing and FRET data) Dissipation and stress relaxation due to unfolding of domains.</td><td>Solid-like at long times as unfolded domains can take load unlike detached crosslinks.</td><td>Peak in relaxation time vs strain because unfolding rate increases with force while re-folding rate decreases with force.</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>