<table-wrap xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="table1" position="float"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.47433.003</object-id><label>Table 1.</label><caption><title>Early adverse conditions and the frequencies with which they occur in maternal and offspring generations of our dataset.</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th rowspan="2" valign="top">Adverse Condition<sup>*</sup></th><th rowspan="2" valign="top">Criterion</th><th colspan="2" valign="top">Frequency</th></tr><tr><th valign="top">&#8195;<italic>Maternal Generation</italic></th><th valign="top"><italic>Offspring Generation</italic></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td valign="top">Drought</td><td valign="top">During the first year of life, the focal individual experienced less than 200 mm of rainfall (i.e., drought conditions; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib15">Beehner et al., 2006</xref>).</td><td valign="top">0.09</td><td valign="top">0.15</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">High Social Density</td><td valign="top">The individual was born into a group with a high social density (&gt;35 adults), indicating high levels of within-group competition.</td><td valign="top">0.06</td><td valign="top">0.32</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Maternal Loss</td><td valign="top">The mother of the focal individual died within four years of the individual&#8217;s birth.</td><td valign="top">0.21</td><td valign="top">0.25</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Low Maternal Rank<bold><sup>&#8224;</sup></bold></td><td valign="top">The focal individual was born to a mother with a low social rank (mother&#8217;s rank fell in the bottom quartile of the group&#8217;s dominance hierarchy, rank&#160;&lt;&#160;0.25).</td><td valign="top">0.17</td><td valign="top">0.23</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Close-In-Age Younger Sibling<sup>&#8225;</sup></td><td valign="top">The focal individual had a younger sibling born to its mother within 18 months of the focal&#8217;s birth.</td><td valign="top">0.20</td><td valign="top">--</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn><p><sup>*</sup>These criteria were used in a previous analysis in our population (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib81">Tung et al., 2016</xref>), with the exception of maternal rank, which is evaluated here as a proportional measure rather than an ordinal one as in the previous analysis.</p><p><sup>&#8224;</sup>Proportional rank is the proportion of other adult females in a group that an individual&#8217;s mother outranks. The reduced frequency with which low maternal rank appears in the maternal generation is a likely a result of offspring of low-ranking mothers surviving less well (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib75">Silk et al., 2003</xref>), and therefore not surviving to appear as mothers in our dataset.</p></fn><fn><p><sup>&#8225;</sup>We excluded the birth of a close-in-age younger sibling for the offspring generation to avoid including a potential reverse-causal factor in our model: the closest-in-age siblings in our dataset occur as a result of the focal offspring&#8217;s death, because female baboons (who are not seasonal reproducers) accelerate their next conception after the death of a dependent offspring.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap>