<table-wrap xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="table1" position="float"><label>Table 1.</label><caption><title>Recommendations.</title><p>Seven concrete actions for department leadership with examples.</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th>Guideline</th><th colspan="2">Examples</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td colspan="2" valign="bottom">1. Supplemental Mentorship</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Departments should require at least one other mentor figure beyond the main supervisor, or the creation of a mentorship committee for graduate students and postdocs.</td><td valign="top">The University of Michigan has recently piloted a mentorship committee program for postdocs (<italic>M. Swanson, personal communication, May 2020).</italic></td></tr><tr><td colspan="2" valign="bottom">2. Peer Support</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Departments should facilitate peer cohorts for social support and peer mentorship, particularly where training start times are not synchronized, such as for postdocs.</td><td valign="top">The <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.uab.edu/cas/sociology/graduate-programs/mentoring-and-advising">Department of Sociology at the University of Alabama at Birmingham</ext-link>&#160;provides all incoming graduate students with peer mentors. While <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://uwpa.wisc.edu/badger-buddies-peer-mentoring/">UW-Madison</ext-link> and&#160;<ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.nature.com/articles/nbt.3631">Brigham and Women's Hospital</ext-link> have postdoc peer mentorship opportunities, these are not incorporated into training/departmental programming.</td></tr><tr><td colspan="2" valign="bottom">3. Required Mentor Training</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Departments should require mentor training not merely as a compliance exercise, but as an investment into the professional development of their faculty, staff, and senior trainees.</td><td valign="top">All basic science graduate science programs at <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://mentoring.ucsf.edu/graduate-program-requirements">UCSF</ext-link> require faculty to participate "in at least one mentorship development activity of their choosing each year they have a student in their lab."</td></tr><tr><td colspan="2" valign="bottom">4. Exit Surveys</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Departments should require anonymous exit surveys from all trainees and staff, publishing aggregate data to ensure the transparent reporting of a department&#8217;s climate; diversity and inclusion efforts; bullying and harassment; and trainee mental health.</td><td valign="top">To date, 53 schools have signed onto the <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://nglscoalition.org/coalition-data/">NGLS</ext-link> coalition to "collect and publish data using common standards on their life science training programs." We highlight the <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.unco.edu/graduate-school/about-us/graduate-school-survey-results.aspx">University of Northern Colorado</ext-link> for publishing thorough information on student satisfaction with the program, research advisor, and factors associated with choosing their field of study.</td></tr><tr><td colspan="2" valign="bottom">5. Clear Guidelines and Timelines</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Departments should provide graduate students and postdocs with clear guidelines and timelines, beyond grad student qualifying exams; the timing of career stage advancement should not solely depend on the main supervisor or thesis committee.</td><td valign="top">Universities in the United Kingdom, such as <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.ox.ac.uk/admissions/graduate/courses/medical-sciences?wssl=1">Oxford</ext-link> and <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.ucl.ac.uk/prospective-students/graduate/research-degrees/biosciences-bbsrc-london-interdisciplinary-consortium-phd">UCL</ext-link>, have PhD thesis submission deadlines of 3&#8211;4 years. <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.einstein.yu.edu/download/?token=yrOWZlEZNMeLBhO0j6BXOdST/w9vBe5SNC2t0dlqYJo">Albert Einstein College of Medicine</ext-link> has a committee that &#8220;reviews the progress of all students who have been in the program for five years or longer and requests an Exit Strategy from [them]".</td></tr><tr><td colspan="2" valign="bottom">6. Standard and Transparent Salary and Benefits</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Departments should provide trainees with benefits and salaries adjusted for the local cost of living, along with transparent and standardized benchmarks for raises based on years of training.</td><td valign="top">To our knowledge, the <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.training.nih.gov/postdoctoral_irta_stipend_ranges">NIH Office of Intramural Training and Education</ext-link> is the only place in the United States that enforces standardized benefits and salary floors, adjusted for years of experience, for both PhDs and postdocs.</td></tr><tr><td colspan="2" valign="bottom">7. Career and Professional Development Resources</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Departments should require trainees to participate in career and professional development training and workshops of their choice, allowing for exploration of careers beyond academia.</td><td valign="top">While many schools provide career development opportunities, we highlight the <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.umassmed.edu/gsbs/career/educators/umms/">Graduate School of Biomedical Science at UMass Medical School</ext-link> for their career development curriculum built into the PhD training program.</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>