<table-wrap xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="table1" position="float"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.28974.008</object-id><label>Table 1.</label><caption><title>Exit questionnaires</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th valign="top"/><th valign="top">1. what did you think the study was about?</th><th valign="top">2. what were you doing during the scans? (Ask about each day if applicable)</th><th valign="top">3. how hard were you trying to solve the puzzles, on a scale of 1&#8211;10, for each day?</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td valign="top">1</td><td valign="top">Really don&#8217;t know. Figure out how long it takes my brain to figure out where all the pieces go.</td><td valign="top">Laying back, relaxing, thinking about random things. Same all days.</td><td valign="top">5, 5, 5, 5</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">2</td><td valign="top">MRIs, puzzle study</td><td valign="top">Day1: just think, Day 2: just think, Day 3: stay awake, Day4: stay awake</td><td valign="top">9, 9, 9, 9</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">3</td><td valign="top">Pictures and the emotional responses they elicit. Definitely tied to emotions. Thought he had to be less excited for pieces to come up</td><td valign="top">Thinking about memories, things to pass the time</td><td valign="top">10, 10, 9, 8</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">4</td><td valign="top">Measuring the thought processes of where certain processes take place in the game. Stress test</td><td valign="top">Day1: eye movement, control heart rate, close eyes; Day2: nothing, relaxed; day3: relax, day4: nothing</td><td valign="top">5, 1, 1, 2</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">5</td><td valign="top">About focus</td><td valign="top">Trying to focus on certain areas of the screen</td><td valign="top">5, 8, 10, 2</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">6</td><td valign="top">What exactly is autism and how the brain is related to it? The puzzles can show how fast different people's brains work.</td><td valign="top">Nothing different really. Today was thinking about an English assignment. Was really just looking at them, wanted to see the picture. Didn't think &#8216;oh I have to do this now&#8217;. Wasn&#8217;t trying hard to solve at all. Either it comes or it doesn&#8217;t. You can't really rush your brain</td><td valign="top">1, 1, 1, 1</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">7</td><td valign="top">I don&#8217;t know</td><td valign="top">Breathing in patterns, blinking, gave up</td><td valign="top">7, 4, 5, 10</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">8</td><td valign="top">About first level visual processing?</td><td valign="top">Most math, computation</td><td valign="top">5, 2, 2, 2</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">9</td><td valign="top">Multitasking, and being able to keep still and look in the same place for a consistent period.</td><td valign="top">Tried different ways to solve more pieces. Today, for example, tried to keep still and look at a similar spot consistently. Yesterday, tried multitasking, breathing and blinking on different rhythmic scales (helped the most). Last week, kept looking around in various directions, mostly at squares that werent filled in yet.</td><td valign="top">6, 6, 7, 8</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">10</td><td valign="top">How humans see stuff and how the brain reacts. Ie sight</td><td valign="top">Staring at whatever space he could to put the puzzle together</td><td valign="top">Same each day</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">11</td><td valign="top">Don&#8217;t know, detecting how hard my brain works on puzzles</td><td valign="top">Trial and error, look at different parts of screen, try different techniques</td><td valign="top">9, 7, 9, 8</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>