<table-wrap xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="table1" position="float"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.47014.002</object-id><label>Table 1.</label><caption><title>The Pittsburgh model of function.</title><p>The hierarchical order of the meanings did not directly derive from our textual analysis, but was inspired from a reductionist interpretation of the flow of genetic information over time and space. It also reflects a possible ordering of the series of properties that must be acquired by a locus to undergo de novo gene birth.</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th>Meanings</th><th valign="top">Definitions</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Evolutionary Implications</td><td valign="top">The object's influence on population dynamics over successive generations, as enabled by its physiological implications and their interplay with environmental pressures</td></tr><tr><td>Physiological Implications</td><td valign="top">The object's involvement in biological processes as enabled by a set of its capacities, interactions and expression patterns, independent of cross-generational considerations</td></tr><tr><td>Interactions</td><td valign="top">Physical contacts, direct or indirect, between the object under investigation and the other components of a system, including contacts that mediate chemical transformations</td></tr><tr><td>Capacities</td><td valign="top">Intrinsic physical properties of the object under investigation; the necessity of the object's behavior given an environment (eg., structural constraints)</td></tr><tr><td>Expression</td><td valign="top">The presence or amount of the object under investigation (RNA or protein object), or the presence or amount of its transcription or translation products (DNA object)</td></tr><tr><td>Vague</td><td valign="top">Sufficient evidence was not found to infer one or more meanings of function within this model, nor to derive a new meaning</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>