<table-wrap xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="Atbl1" position="float"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.19505.019</object-id><label>Appendix 1&#8212;table 1.</label><caption><p>Features (predictor variables) used in conditional logistic regression models to predict baboon movement decisions.</p><p><bold>DOI:</bold> <ext-link ext-link-type="doi" xlink:href="10.7554/eLife.19505.019">http://dx.doi.org/10.7554/eLife.19505.019</ext-link></p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th>Feature</th><th>Description</th><th>Range</th><th>Considered as:</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Environment density</td><td>Fraction of raster pixels containing non-ground points within a specified radius (<italic>R</italic> = 2.5 m) from the potential location (a proxy for vegetation density)</td><td>[0,&#160;1] <break/><break/></td><td>Habitat Feature</td></tr><tr><td>Social density</td><td>Fraction of baboons currently tracked within a specified radius (<italic>R<sub>soc</sub></italic> = 4.25 m) of the potential location</td><td>[0,&#160;1] <break/><break/></td><td>Social Feature</td></tr><tr><td>Sleep site direction</td><td>The dot product of the direction vector from the current location to the potential location and the vector from the current location to the sleep site location. This quantity ranges from &#8722;1 (potential step is in the direct opposite direction from the sleep site) to 1 (potential step is directly toward the sleep site). The influence of the sleep site is expected to vary with time of day, therefore it is fit as an interaction with time of day, yielding three parameters. Times of day included Morning (9&#160;am&#8211;12&#160;pm), Midday (12&#8211;3&#160;pm), and Evening (3&#8211;6&#160;pm)</td><td>[&#8722;1,&#160;1] <break/><break/></td><td>Habitat Feature</td></tr><tr><td>Roads</td><td>A binary predictor indicating whether the potential location is on a road or not. The influence of roads is expected to vary with whether an individual is currently on the road or not, therefore it is fit as an interaction with whether the baboon&#8217;s current location is on a road (also a binary value), yielding two parameters</td><td>{0,&#160;1} <break/><break/></td><td>Habitat Feature</td></tr><tr><td>Recently-used space</td><td>An integer indicating how many other baboons (not including the focal individual) have recently (within the past 4.5 min) occupied the potential location, where a baboon is considered to be&#160;'occupying a location' if its position is within 1 m of that location</td><td>{0,&#160;&#8230;,&#160;<italic>N</italic>} <break/><break/></td><td>Social Feature</td></tr><tr><td>Ever-used space</td><td>A binary variable that is defined as 1 if the location, was ever occupied by another baboon (not the focal baboon) throughout the entire dataset, (past, present, and future)</td><td>{0,&#160;1} <break/><break/></td><td>Both</td></tr><tr><td>Animal paths</td><td>A binary variable indicating whether a potential location is on an animal path (1) or not (0). It is fit as an interaction with whether the baboon&#8217;s current location is on a path (also a binary value), yielding two parameters</td><td>{0,&#160;1} <break/><break/></td><td>Habitat feature</td></tr><tr><td>Visible neighbors</td><td>A continuous variable that indicates the fraction of other group members that are visible from a given location at the time of the step. Group members were defined as visible if a line drawn from the potential location to their location at the relevant time does not pass through any raster cells containing non-ground points.</td><td>[0,&#160;1] <break/><break/></td><td>Social feature</td></tr><tr><td>Slope</td><td>The change in elevation (in meters) from the starting location to a potential location</td><td>(&#8722;&#8734;,&#160;&#8734;) <break/><break/></td><td>Habitat feature</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>