<table-wrap xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="tbl1" position="float"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.19505.003</object-id><label>Table 1.</label><caption><p>Features (predictor variables) used in conditional logistic regression models to predict baboon movement decisions.</p><p><bold>DOI:</bold> <ext-link ext-link-type="doi" xlink:href="10.7554/eLife.19505.003">http://dx.doi.org/10.7554/eLife.19505.003</ext-link></p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th>Feature</th><th>Description</th><th>Type</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Environment density</td><td>Fraction of non-ground (vegetated) area within a 2.5 m* radius of a potential location</td><td>Habitat Feature</td></tr><tr><td>Social density</td><td>Fraction of all troop mates within a 4.25 m* radius of a potential location</td><td>Social Feature</td></tr><tr><td>Sleep site direction</td><td>Direction of a potential location relative to the sleep site, ranges from &#8722;1 (directly away) to 1 (directly toward), fit as interaction with time of day</td><td>Habitat Feature</td></tr><tr><td>Roads</td><td>Whether a potential location is on a road (1) or not (0). Fit as an interaction with whether the baboon&#8217;s previous location was on a road</td><td>Habitat Feature</td></tr><tr><td>Recently-used space</td><td>Number of other baboons (not including focal individual) that have occupied a potential location within the past 4.5 min*</td><td>Social Feature</td></tr><tr><td>Ever-used space</td><td>Whether a potential location was ever occupied by another baboon (not including focal individual) across the entire dataset</td><td>Both</td></tr><tr><td>Animal paths</td><td>Whether a potential location is on an animal path (1) or not (0), fit as interaction with whether baboon&#8217;s previous location was on a path</td><td>Habitat Feature</td></tr><tr><td>Visible neighbors</td><td>Fraction of other group members visible from a potential location (i.e. direct line-of-sight does not pass through any vegetated areas)</td><td>Social Feature</td></tr><tr><td>Slope</td><td>Change in elevation to a potential location from the baboon&#8217;s previous location</td><td>Habitat Feature</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn id="tblfn1"><p>*Spatial and temporal scales were determined using maximum likelihood in a preliminary analysis. See Supplementary methods and <xref ref-type="table" rid="Atbl1">Appendix 1&#8212;table 1</xref> for further details.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap>