<table-wrap xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="table8" position="float"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.36842.033</object-id><label>Table 8.</label><caption><title>List of suggested experiments, with rationale behind each suggestion.</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th>Experiment</th><th>Rationale</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><italic>Nutrient utilization</italic></td><td/></tr><tr><td> Detect lipoylpeptide uptake</td><td>Lipoate is cofactor for PDH, whose functionality is unclear after E1 subunit deletion.</td></tr><tr><td> Detect nucleotide uptake</td><td>Activity reported for <italic>M. mycoides capri</italic> without gene assignment; alternative routes present in JCVI-syn3A, but activity not ruled out.</td></tr><tr><td> Detect nucleobase uptake</td><td>Activity reported for <italic>M. mycoides capri</italic>, and uracil uptake essential in model.</td></tr><tr><td> Demonstrate growth on thiamine diphosphate</td><td>Structural data and deletion of thiamine diphosphokinase suggest thiamine diphosphate (ThDP) uptake. Inability to grow on ThDP would imply unidentified kinase activity.</td></tr><tr><td> Demonstrate growth on pyridoxal phosphate</td><td>With no pyridoxal kinase identified, growth on pyridoxal phosphate (P5P) assumed; inability to grow on P5P would imply unidentified kinase activity.</td></tr><tr><td> Demonstrate growth on acetylmannosamine</td><td>Reconstruction suggests operon 0493 through 0495 to be <italic>nagA</italic>/<italic>nanE</italic>/<italic>nagC</italic>; growth on acetylmannosamine would support assignment and imply uptake capability.</td></tr><tr><td> Demonstrate growth on mannose or glucosamine</td><td>Literature suggests mannose and glucosamine import through PtsG; and downstream enzymes are present.</td></tr><tr><td><italic>Metabolite production/secretion</italic></td><td/></tr><tr><td> Detect production of acetate</td><td>Acetate pathway has been partially removed, but several of the remaining enzymes remain essential in transposon mutagenesis experiments.</td></tr><tr><td> Investigate production of lipogalactan capsule</td><td>Genetic evidence suggests capsule is still being produced.</td></tr><tr><td> Detect secretion of deoxyuridine or dUMP</td><td>Deoxyuridine/dUMP is currently dead-end; secretion would be one possible solution.</td></tr><tr><td><italic>Enzymatic activity</italic></td><td/></tr><tr><td> Detect pyruvate oxidation</td><td>Conversion of pyruvate to acetyl-CoA by truncated PDH complex has been assumed for the time being but is not supported by experiment.</td></tr><tr><td> Detect oxidation of acetaldehyde</td><td>Conversion of acetaldehyde to acetyl-CoA would provide alternative explanation for presence of truncated PDH complex in JCVI-syn3A in spite of deletion of first subunit.</td></tr><tr><td> Detect NOX activity</td><td>NADH oxidase (NOX) has been deleted but activity would be necessary for PDH activity against both pyruvate and acetaldehyde.</td></tr><tr><td> Detect transaldolase activity</td><td>Activity is essential in model and has been detected in <italic>M. mycoides capri</italic>; no known gene in any mycoplasma though.</td></tr><tr><td> Detect sedoheptulose-1,7-bisphosphate phosphatase activity</td><td>Reaction would provide bypass to transaldolase reaction.</td></tr><tr><td> Detect phosphatidate phosphatase activity</td><td>Gene present in <italic>M. pneumoniae</italic> and reaction is missing link to diacylglycerol, but no gene identified in JCVI-syn3A.</td></tr><tr><td> Assess phosphatase activity against dCTP, dCDP, GMP, dAMP, dGMP, dUMP, dTMP; pyrophosphatase activity against CTP, dCTP</td><td>Activities observed in <italic>M. mycoides capri</italic> but no gene identified in JCVI-syn3A.</td></tr><tr><td>&#8194;Detect deoxyuridine phosphorylase activity</td><td>Gene has been removed in JCVI-syn3A (MMSYN1_0734), but deoxyuridine/dUMP is currently dead-end, raising the question whether function is carried out by some other gene.</td></tr><tr><td> Detect thymidylate synthase activity</td><td>Extremely low activity detected in <italic>M. mycoides mycoides</italic> SC, but no gene identified. Reaction would be alternative solution to deoxyuridine/dUMP dead-end.</td></tr><tr><td><italic>Specific gene function</italic></td><td/></tr><tr><td> Determine substrates for deoxynucleoside kinase <italic>dak2/</italic>0382</td><td>Presence of <italic>dak2/</italic>0382 in addition to the characterized <italic>dak1/</italic>0330 suggests different substrate profile.</td></tr><tr><td> Verify CTPS activity against dUMP</td><td>CTPS (<italic>pyrG/</italic>0129) converting dUMP to dCMP seems most plausible solution to deoxyuridine/dUMP dead-end.</td></tr><tr><td> Check PGPP activity against phosphatidate</td><td>Activity observed for PgpB in <italic>E. coli</italic>; activity for PGPP (<italic>pgpA/</italic>0214) would provide missing link to diacylglycerol in apparent absence of phosphatidate phosphatase gene.</td></tr><tr><td> Check UMPK activity against CMP and dCMP</td><td>Substrate profile for UMP kinase similar to eukaryotic enzyme could explain quasi-essentiality of CMP kinase.</td></tr><tr><td><italic>Change of expression levels</italic></td><td/></tr><tr><td> Knock out deoxynucleoside kinases and over express RNDR</td><td>RNDR and deoxynucleoside kinases provide redundant routes to deoxydinucleotides, suggesting one pathway might be sufficient if expression increased.</td></tr><tr><td> Reduce expression of RNDR and knock out putative dUTPase simultaneously</td><td>RNDR is currently only known source of dUTP. If RNDR knockdown would make the putative dUTPase gene <italic>dut/</italic>0447 nonessential as well, this would corroborate the putative assignment.</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>