<table-wrap xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="table1" position="float"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.40162.026</object-id><label>Table 1.</label><caption><title>Summary of MOSES-derived measurements for discriminating boundary formation phenotype in this paper and their biological interpretation and application.</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th>Proposed measures</th><th>Biological interpretation</th><th>Biological application</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Motion Saliency Map</td><td>&#8216;Heatmap&#8217;-like image that highlights spatial regions that attract or repel local cellular motion over a defined time period.</td><td>Quantitative spatio-temporal readout of scratch or wound-healing assays. Highlights areas of salient motion activity spatially such as the migration of macrophages locally to inflicted wound sites.</td></tr><tr><td>Boundary formation index (value from 0 to 1)</td><td>Quantifies the concentration of movement within one region of space. Multiple &#8216;hotspots&#8217; decrease this index. Uniform distributed movement (no attraction) scores 0. Concentration of movement in a single region for&#160;example a line or point scores 1.</td><td>Quantification of the spatial uniformity or &#8216;spread&#8217; of motion activity. Highlights for example if all migrating cells move uniformly to close the wound in a wound-healing assay.</td></tr><tr><td>Mesh stability index (value from <inline-formula><mml:math id="inf21"><mml:mo>-</mml:mo><mml:mi mathvariant="bold-italic"/></mml:math></inline-formula>&#8734; to 1)</td><td>Measures the motion stability of local cell groups by measuring the change in relative spatial arrangement (topology) with respect to neighbouring cell groups at a given endpoint. Static epithelial sheets and epithelial sheets that move uniformly in a single direction preserve local cellular arrangement and&#160;scores 1.&#160;Motion that results&#160;in the local spatial&#160;rearrangement of cells such as neighbour exchange in embryos is unstable and scores&#160;&lt;&#160;1.</td><td>Assessing the final global movement stability of a collective such as an embryo or epithelial sheet based on the movement of the cells that compose it.</td></tr><tr><td>Mesh order (value&#160;&gt;&#160;0)</td><td>Measures the collectiveness of local cellular migration by the change in distance and direction of cells with respect to neighbouring cells. Hypothesizes that&#160;cells that&#160;are&#160;part of the same motion group exhibit the same &#8216;mesh&#8217; force and move retaining the same local spatial arrangement.</td><td>Quantitative assessment of the extent of global sheet-like movement.</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>