<table-wrap xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="table1" position="float"><label>Table 1.</label><caption><title>Evaluation of the reporting of imaging methods in biomedical journals.</title><p>The first column lists journal name, number of articles with images, number of articles evaluated, and the percentage of articles with images. The second column lists the percentage of figures (main and supplemental) that contain original images or quantification of imaging data. The third column lists the percentage of text in the materials and methods sections devoted to imaging (for the 185 articles that contained images). The fourth column lists the percentage of the articles containing images that pass the methods quality test (see Materials and methods for details of this test). Total developmental biology includes three journals (Dev. Biol., Development, and Dev. Cell); total immunology includes two journals (Nature Immunology and J. Immunology). * Five articles containing MRI and X-ray images were not included in the quality evaluation, so the sample for this analysis is 180 papers. <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="supp1">Supplementary file 1</xref> contains a list of all the articles analyzed and details for each article.</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th valign="top">Journal (articles with imaging/total articles, percentage)</th><th valign="top">Imaging figures (%)</th><th valign="top">Imaging methods (%)</th><th valign="top">Pass methods quality (%)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Developmental Biology (29/30, 99%)</td><td>79</td><td>4.2</td><td>3.4</td></tr><tr><td>Development (28/28, 100%)</td><td>75</td><td>7.0</td><td>14.3</td></tr><tr><td>Developmental Cell (32/32, 100%)</td><td>69</td><td>4.8</td><td>9.4</td></tr><tr><td>J Cell Biology (29/30, 97%)</td><td>72</td><td>10.1</td><td>37.9</td></tr><tr><td>Nature Immunology (18/29, 62%)</td><td>22</td><td>5.5</td><td>11.1</td></tr><tr><td>J Immunology (17/31, 55%)</td><td>21</td><td>2.3</td><td>5.9</td></tr><tr><td>J Neuroscience (18/30, 60%)</td><td>37</td><td>7.8</td><td>7.1</td></tr><tr><td>Biophysical Journal (14/30, 47%)</td><td>28</td><td>10.2</td><td>50.0</td></tr><tr><td>Total developmental biology <break/>(89/90, 99%)</td><td>74</td><td>5.2</td><td>9.0</td></tr><tr><td>Total immunolgy <break/>(35/60, 58%)</td><td>21</td><td>4.6</td><td>8.6</td></tr><tr><td>Total (185/240)</td><td>52</td><td>6.7</td><td>16.7<sup>(*)</sup></td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>