<table-wrap xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="tbl1" position="float"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.19130.008</object-id><label>Table 1.</label><caption><p>Pathway enrichment analysis of genes with significant correlation with the longevity traits.</p><p>The genes were supported by at least two longevity traits (p value.robust&#160;&lt;&#160;0.01 and p value.max&#160;&lt;&#160;0.05). Pathway enrichment was performed using DAVID. The percentages of positive or negative correlating genes belonging to each pathway were indicated in parentheses. Only selected pathways are shown here. GO (BP): Gene Ontology (Biological Process). GO (BP): Gene Ontology (Molecular Functions). SP/PIR: SwissProt and Protein Information Resource. See <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SD2-data">Table 1&#8212;source data 1</xref> for more details.</p><p><bold>DOI:</bold> <ext-link ext-link-type="doi" xlink:href="10.7554/eLife.19130.008">http://dx.doi.org/10.7554/eLife.19130.008</ext-link></p><p><supplementary-material id="SD2-data"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.19130.009</object-id><label>Table 1&#8212;source data 1.</label><caption><title>Phylogenetic regression of gene expression against longevity traits.</title><p>Regression against (<bold>A</bold>) Adult Weight; (<bold>B</bold>) Maximum Lifespan; (<bold>C</bold>) Female Time to Maturity; (<bold>D</bold>) Maximum Lifespan Residual; and (<bold>E</bold>) Female Time to Maturity Residual. &#8216;coef.all&#8217;, &#8216;p value.all&#8217;, and &#8216;q value.all&#8217; refer to the regression slope, p value, and FDR-adjusted q value using all the species. &#8216;p value.robust&#8217; and &#8216;q value.robust&#8217; refer to the statistics after removing the potential outlier point. &#8216;p value.max&#8217; and &#8216;q value.max&#8217; refer to the maximal (least significant) regression p value and q value when each one of the species was left out, one at a time. Only genes with p value.robust&lt;0.01 and p value.max&lt;0.05 are shown. (<bold>F</bold>) Top hits identified by two or more longevity traits. The p value.robust against each of the four longevity traits (ML, FTM, MLres, and FTMres) as well as adult weight (AW) are shown. These genes were the input for pathway enrichment analysis. Pathway enrichment analysis of genes showing (<bold>G</bold>) positive and (<bold>H</bold>) negative correlation with longevity traits. Enrichment was performed using DAVID with default settings. Only the top 10 clusters are shown. (<bold>I</bold>) System level analyses of gene functions. The numbers of shared genes between longevity associated genes (either positively or negatively or both) and human aging genes, essential genes, transcription factor genes, and housekeeping genes are shown. The enrichment p value was calculated by Fisher&#8217;s exact test with two different background gene sets.</p><p><bold>DOI:</bold> <ext-link ext-link-type="doi" xlink:href="10.7554/eLife.19130.009">http://dx.doi.org/10.7554/eLife.19130.009</ext-link></p></caption><media mime-subtype="xlsx" mimetype="application" xlink:href="elife-19130-table1-data1-v2.xlsx"/></supplementary-material></p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th><p><bold>Annotation cluster</bold></p> </th><th><p><bold>Enriched terms and genes</bold></p> </th><th><p><bold>No. of genes</bold></p> </th><th><p><bold>p Value</bold></p> </th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td rowspan="3"><p>Positive Correlation</p><p>Cluster No. 1</p><p>(15%)</p></td><td valign="top"><p>GO (MF):&#160;adenyl nucleotide binding</p></td><td valign="top"><p>50</p></td><td valign="top"><p>5.25&#160;&#215;&#160;10<sup>&#8722;3</sup></p></td></tr><tr><td valign="top"><p>GO (MF):&#160;nucleotide binding</p></td><td valign="top"><p>64</p></td><td valign="top"><p>1.21&#160;&#215;&#160;10<sup>&#8722;2</sup></p></td></tr><tr><td colspan="3" valign="top"><p><italic>Acly, Atad2, Atp2b4, Cdk2, Cdk20, Chd7, Chek1, Chkb, Cpsf7, D2hgdh, Dgkq, Dhx58, Dock6, Ero1lb, Etnk1, Fastkd5, Fn3krp, Gnai1, Guk1, Hk1, Hmgcr, Hnrnpd, Hyou1, Insr, Madd, Map4k5, Mastl, Mlkl, Mov10, Msh6, Mx2, Nadsyn1, Oplah, Pdk1, Pfkp, Phka2, Phkg2, Pkmyt1, Pms2, Pnkp, Ppp2r4, Prkar1b, Qrsl1, Rbm10, Rbm15b, Rbm38, Rhot2, Rnasel, Rps6ka2, Sacs, Sirt3, Slirp, Smarca1, Smarca5, Srsf9, Stk19, Stk36, Tbrg4, Tesk2, Thnsl1, Tia1, Top3a, Trpm4, Ttf2, Tyk2, Vps4a, Ythdc2</italic></p> </td></tr><tr><td rowspan="4"><p>Positive Correlation</p><p>Cluster No. 2</p><p>(4%)</p></td><td valign="top"><p>SP/PIR:&#160;DNA damage</p></td><td valign="top"><p>14</p></td><td valign="top"><p>1.16&#160;&#215;&#160;10<sup>&#8722;3</sup></p></td></tr><tr><td valign="top"><p>SP/PIR:&#160;DNA repair</p></td><td valign="top"><p>12</p></td><td valign="top"><p>4.25&#160;&#215;&#160;10<sup>&#8722;3</sup></p></td></tr><tr><td valign="top"><p>GO (BP):&#160;cellular response to stress</p></td><td valign="top"><p>16</p></td><td valign="top"><p>1.01&#160;&#215;&#160;10<sup>&#8722;1</sup></p></td></tr><tr><td colspan="3" valign="top"><p><italic>Bnip3, C17orf70, Chek1, Dtx3l, Ercc1, Errfi1, Fancg, Hif1a, Mapkbp1, Msh6, Myd88, Pms2, Pnkp, Prdx3, Prpf19, Pttg1, Rad51b, Rif1, Rnaseh1, Slx4, Tdp2, Terf1, Tinf2, Top3a, Wrap53</italic></p> </td></tr><tr><td rowspan="4"><p>Positive Correlation</p><p>Cluster No. 4/5</p><p>(4%)</p></td><td valign="top"><p>GO (BP):&#160;glucose metabolic process</p></td><td valign="top"><p>11</p></td><td valign="top"><p>1.22&#160;&#215;&#160;10<sup>&#8722;3</sup></p></td></tr><tr><td valign="top"><p>GO (BP):&#160;hexose metabolic process</p></td><td valign="top"><p>11</p></td><td valign="top"><p>5.68&#160;&#215;&#160;10<sup>&#8722;3</sup></p></td></tr><tr><td valign="top"><p>GO (BP):&#160;generation of precursor metabolites and energy</p></td><td valign="top"><p>15</p></td><td valign="top"><p>4.59&#160;&#215;&#160;10<sup>&#8722;3</sup></p></td></tr><tr><td colspan="3" valign="top"><p><italic>Aldh5a1, Atp2b4, Atp6v0d1, Atp6v0e2, Ero1lb, Fads1, Gbe1, Gpi1, Hexa, Hk1, Insr, Ndst1, Ndufa8, Pdk1, Pfkp, Pgp, Phka2, Phkb, Phkg2, Prkar1b, Sdhaf3, Tmx4, Tpi1, Trpm4, Tsc2</italic></p> </td></tr><tr><td rowspan="3"><p>Positive Correlation</p><p>Cluster No. 6</p><p>(4%)</p></td><td valign="top"><p>SP/PIR:&#160;chromatin regulator</p></td><td valign="top"><p>11</p></td><td valign="top"><p>1.61&#160;&#215;&#160;10<sup>&#8722;2</sup></p></td></tr><tr><td valign="top"><p>GO (BP):&#160;chromosome organization</p></td><td valign="top"><p>17</p></td><td valign="top"><p>2.22&#160;&#215;&#160;10<sup>&#8722;2</sup></p></td></tr><tr><td colspan="3" valign="top"><p><italic>Bnip3, Cenph, Chd7, Dtx3l, Ercc1, H2afv, Hdac2, Jade1, Kdm5d, Kmt2c, Pttg1, Rcor1, Rrp8, Smarca1, Smarca5, Smyd3, Terf1, Tinf2, Wdr5, Wrap53</italic></p> </td></tr><tr><td rowspan="4"><p>Negative Correlation</p><p>Cluster No. 1</p><p>(9%)</p></td><td valign="top"><p>GO (BP):&#160;modification-dependent protein catabolic process</p></td><td valign="top"><p>27</p></td><td valign="top"><p>2.39&#160;&#215;&#160;10<sup>&#8722;4</sup></p></td></tr><tr><td valign="top"><p>SP/PIR:&#160;ubiquitin conjugation pathway</p></td><td valign="top"><p>26</p></td><td valign="top"><p>3.35&#160;&#215;&#160;10<sup>&#8722;4</sup></p></td></tr><tr><td valign="top"><p>GO (BP):&#160;proteolysis</p></td><td valign="top"><p>36</p></td><td valign="top"><p>1.09&#160;&#215;&#160;10<sup>&#8722;2</sup></p></td></tr><tr><td colspan="3" valign="top"><p><italic>Adamts2, Agtpbp1, Anapc4, Atg10, Atg4a, Atg7, Btbd1, Ctsl, Ctsz, Dcaf10, Dda1, Dpp8, Fbxl17, Fbxl20, Fbxo18, Fbxw2, Kcmf1, Map1lc3b, Med8, Mmp2, Mycbp2, Oma1, Pcsk5, Pgpep1, Pmepa1, Ppp2r5c, Rad18, Rfwd2, Rnf14, Rnf2, Rnf6, Sumo3, Tpp2, Ube2b, Ube2v1, Ufm1, Vhl</italic></p> </td></tr><tr><td rowspan="3"><p>Negative Correlation</p><p>Cluster No. 2</p><p>(9%)</p></td><td valign="top"><p>GO (BP):&#160;protein localization</p></td><td valign="top"><p>38</p></td><td valign="top"><p>4.67&#160;&#215;&#160;10<sup>&#8722;5</sup></p></td></tr><tr><td valign="top"><p>GO (BP):&#160;protein transport</p></td><td valign="top"><p>34</p></td><td valign="top"><p>7.99&#160;&#215;&#160;10<sup>&#8722;5</sup></p></td></tr><tr><td colspan="3" valign="top"><p><italic>Agap1, Akap7, Ap3d1, Atg10, Atg4a, Atg7, Bax, Cav1, Clpx, Cnih1, Col4a3bp, Cry2, Dirc2, Ergic2, Fdx1l, Fkbp15, Gabarapl2, Gdi2, Gm10273, Golt1b, Hspa9, Ift46, Ipo4, Kif1bp, Kpna4, Laptm4a, Lrp4, mt-Nd4, Mtch1, Ndel1, Ndufb11, Necap1, Ppp3ca, Rab18, Rab2a, Rab6a, Rhot1, Sar1a, Sec22a, Sec31a, Sec62, Slc25a12, Slc29a1, Slc33a1, Slc35a4, Snx12, Snx13, Stx17, Timm8a1, Tomm6, Trappc6b, Trp53, Tsg101, Vps36, Vps53, Ywhag</italic></p> </td></tr><tr><td rowspan="3"><p>Negative Correlation</p><p>Cluster No. 3</p><p>(18%)</p></td><td valign="top"><p>GO (BP):&#160;regulation of transcription</p></td><td valign="top"><p>74</p></td><td valign="top"><p>1.62&#160;&#215;&#160;10<sup>&#8722;5</sup></p></td></tr><tr><td valign="top"><p>SP/PIR:&#160;transcription regulation</p></td><td valign="top"><p>55</p></td><td valign="top"><p>1.04&#160;&#215;&#160;10<sup>&#8722;3</sup></p></td></tr><tr><td colspan="3" valign="top"><p><italic>Actl6a, Agtpbp1, Ak6, Anp32a, Anp32e, Atf6b, Bckdha, Bmi1, Ccdc59, Cd3eap, Cdc5l, Cggbp1, Clk2, Cnbp, Cops7a, Crtc3, Cry2, Csrp2, Ebna1bp2, Ehmt2, Elk4, Ergic2, Fbxo18, Fip1l1, Fosb, Foxo3, Gatad2b, Gid8, Gmcl1, Gtf2h1, Gtf2h2, Gtf2h5, Harbi1, Hlx, Hmga1-rs1, Hnrnpab, Hnrnpf, Ift57, Ing2, Ints4, Ipo4, Jund, Klf11, Klf2, Klf4, Klf9, Kpna4, Mafb, Mapk1, Mdm4, Med16, Med17, Med31, Med8, Mef2a, Mettl8, Mmp2, Mnt, Morf4l2, Mta1, Mtdh, Mxd1, Mycbp2, Nabp2, Ncor2, Neo1, Nfe2l2, Nr1d2, Papd4, Parp2, Phf12, Phlpp1, Pkig, Pomp, Pop5, Ppp1r8, Ppp2r5c, Ppp3ca, Ptbp1, R3hdm4, Rab18, Rad18, Rbbp4, Rfwd2, Rnf14, Rnf2, Rnf6, Rps6ka4, Rrs1, Sap30l, Sav1, Scoc, Sfmbt1, Sin3b, Snrk, Sqstm1, Srpk2, Ssbp1, Tep1, Tgfbr3, Trim35, Trip6, Trp53, Tsg101, Ube2b, Ube2v1, Ubtf, Ufm1, Vhl, Vps36, Wiz, Xrcc5, Yeats4, Zbtb14, Zfp414, Zfp637, Zfp655, Zfp710, Zfp821</italic></p> </td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>