<table-wrap xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="table1" position="float"><label>Table 1.</label><caption><title>Open questions.</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><tbody><tr><td valign="top">Can learned climbing fiber activity drive higher order conditioning to establish motor (or other) sequences?</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Does climbing fiber activity in reward-based learning paradigms follow the same rules that have been shown for VTA dopamine neurons?</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">How are reward-related climbing fiber signals generated? Can they be computed locally in the IO, or inherited from upstream brain regions? If inherited, from where?</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">How are reward-related signals in the granule cells and climbing fibers integrated to mediate learning? How might cerebellar reward-based learning be used by downstream brain regions?</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Does the granule cell layer generate sparse representations of sensorimotor input, and how do local synaptic computations establish such representations?</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Can climbing fibers generate a graded representation of the magnitude of behavioral errors?</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">How does cerebellar learning interact with neocortical circuits, and how to do these circuits bi-directionally modulate one another to guide behavior?</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">How does cerebellar learning modify output to the mesolimbic dopamine system during goal directed behaviors?</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">How does cerebellar circuit dysfunction modulate neocortical developmental and adult neocortical circuit processing in cognitive disease states such as Autism Spectrum Disorders?</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Can cerebellar learning harness different mechanisms and region-specific computations to achieve different goals? Does cerebellar output depend on behavioral or cognitive requirements?</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>