<table-wrap xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="inlinetable1" position="anchor"><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><tbody><tr valign="top"><td>PhyB</td><td>Phytochrome B (photoreceptor of <italic>Arabidopsis thaliana</italic>), here only the first 651 amino acids are used, since this part is sufficient to bind PIF under 660 nm, but not under 740 nm light.</td></tr><tr valign="top"><td>PIF</td><td>PhyB-interacting factor, here the first 100 aa of <italic>A. thaliana</italic> PIF6 are used, since they are sufficient to bind to PhyB.</td></tr><tr valign="top"><td>PIF<sup>S</sup></td><td>A mutant version of functional PIF developed in this study, that can move through the secretory pathway to the cell surface and remain in a functional conformation, i.e., it is still capable of binding PhyB.</td></tr><tr valign="top"><td>PhyBt</td><td>Fluorescently labeled streptavidin-based tetramers of PhyB.</td></tr><tr valign="top"><td>PhyBt(660)</td><td>PhyBt pre-illuminated with 660 nm light, so that equilibrium is reached, in which 80% of the PhyB molecules are in their ON state</td></tr><tr valign="top"><td>PhyBt(740)</td><td>PhyBt pre-illuminated with 740 nm light, so that all PhyB molecules are in the OFF state</td></tr><tr valign="top"><td>PhyB ON</td><td>PhyB in the active conformation allowing binding to PIF with nanomolar affinity (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig1">Figure 1</xref>).</td></tr><tr valign="top"><td>PhyB OFF</td><td>PhyB in the inactive conformation, in which they cannot bind to PIF (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig1">Figure 1</xref>).</td></tr><tr valign="top"><td><sub>&#964;KPR</sub></td><td>The KPR time or KPR duration. The half-life of the bivalent binding of the soluble ligand to the TCR needs to be at least this time to induce downstream, activatory signaling.</td></tr><tr valign="top"><td>moxGFP</td><td>A GFP mutant (S30R, Y29N, C48S, F64L, S65T, C70S, Q80R, F99S, N105T, Y145F, M153T, V163A, I171V, A206K) that was optimized for the folding in the endoplasmic reticulum (ox) and that is expressed as a monomer (m).</td></tr><tr valign="top"><td>TCR</td><td>T cell receptor. The receptor on T cells controlling T cell activation. It consists of the TCR&#945;, TCR&#946;, CD3&#947;, CD3&#948;, CD3&#949;&#160;and &#950;&#160;chains.</td></tr><tr valign="top"><td>PIF<sup>S</sup>-TCR</td><td>A preliminary non-functional TCR chimera, in which PIF<sup>S</sup> is fused to the ectodomain of the TCR&#946;&#160;subunit.</td></tr><tr valign="top"><td>pMHC</td><td>Peptide bound to Major Histocompatibility Complex constitutes the ligand for the TCR.</td></tr><tr valign="top"><td>GFP-PIF<sup>S</sup>-TCR</td><td>Our engineered TCR, in which the moxGFP and PIF<sup>S</sup> are fused to the ectodomain of the TCR&#946;&#160;subunit.</td></tr><tr valign="top"><td>GFP-PIF<sup>S</sup>-TCR cells</td><td>Jurkat E6.1 T cells expressing the GFP-PIF<sup>S</sup>-TCR.</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>