<table-wrap xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="tbl1" position="float"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.23717.005</object-id><label>Table 1.</label><caption><p>Glossary Box.&#160;A schematic figure of eukaryotic taxonomy, showing the evolutionary origins of nuclear and plastid lineages, adapted from previous reviews (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib35">Dorrell and Howe, 2012a</xref>), is shown in <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig1s1">Figure 1&#8212;figure supplement 1</xref>.</p><p><bold>DOI:</bold> <ext-link ext-link-type="doi" xlink:href="10.7554/eLife.23717.005">http://dx.doi.org/10.7554/eLife.23717.005</ext-link></p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><tbody><tr><td valign="top"><bold>Complex plastids</bold></td><td valign="top">Plastids acquired through the endosymbiosis of a eukaryotic alga. These include secondary plastids of ultimate red algal origin (such as those found in ochrophytes, haptophytes and cryptomonads), secondary plastids derived from green algae (such as those found in euglenids or chlorarachniophytes), or tertiary plastids such as those found in dinotoms and certain other dinoflagellates (resulting from the endosymbioses of eukaryotic algae that themselves contain plastids of&#160;complex origin).</td></tr><tr><td valign="top"><bold>CASH lineages</bold></td><td valign="top">The four major lineages of algae with plastids of secondary or higher red origin, that is to say <underline>C</underline>ryptomonads, <underline>A</underline>lveolates (dinoflagellates, and apicomplexans), <underline>S</underline>tramenopiles, and <underline>H</underline>aptophytes.</td></tr><tr><td valign="top"><bold>Stramenopiles</bold></td><td valign="top">A diverse and ecologically major component of the eukaryotic tree, containing both photosynthetic members (the ochrophytes), which possess complex plastids of red algal origin, and aplastidic and non-photosynthetic members (e.g. oomycetes, labyrinthulomycetes, and the human pathogen <italic>Blastocystis</italic>), which form the earliest-diverging branches. It is debated when within stramenopile evolution the extant ochrophyte plastid was acquired.</td></tr><tr><td valign="top"><bold>Ochrophytes</bold></td><td valign="top">Photosynthetic and plastid-bearing members of the stramenopiles, including many ecologically important lineages (diatoms, kelps, pelagophytes) and potential model lineages for biofuels research (<italic>Nannochloropsis</italic>). Ochrophytes possess plastids of ultimate red origin, and form the most significant component of eukaryotic marine phytoplankton (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib39">Dorrell and Smith, 2011</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib28">de Vargas et al., 2015</xref>).</td></tr><tr><td valign="top"><bold>Haptophytes</bold></td><td valign="top">Single-celled, photosynthetic eukaryotes, possessing complex plastids of ultimate red origin. Some haptophytes (the coccolithophorids) are renowned for their ability to form large blooms (visible from space), and to form intricate calcareous shells (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib39">Dorrell and Smith, 2011</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib14">Bown, 1998</xref>), which if deposited on the ocean floor go on to form a major component of limestone and other sedimentary rocks.</td></tr><tr><td valign="top"><bold>HPPG</bold></td><td valign="top">&#8216;Homologous plastid protein group&#8217;. Proteins identified in this study to possess plastid-targeting sequences that are homologous to one another, as defined by BLAST-based HPPG assembly and single gene phylogenetic analysis.</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>