<table-wrap xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="table3" position="float"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.39636.009</object-id><label>Table 3.</label><caption><title>Gene sets enriched in FIPs.</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th valign="top">Gene set name</th><th valign="top">Gene set <break/>description</th><th valign="top">FDR q-value</th><th valign="top">Enriched genes</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td valign="top">HALLMARK_PANCREAS_ <break/>BETA_CELLS</td><td valign="top">Genes specifically up-regulated <break/>in pancreatic beta cells.</td><td valign="top">0</td><td valign="top">DPP4, LMO2, SRP9, SRP14</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">HALLMARK_ <break/>INFLAMMATORY_ <break/>RESPONSE</td><td valign="top">Genes annotated by the GO term GO:0006954. The immediate defensive reaction to infection or injury caused by chemical or physical agents. The process is characterized by local vasodilation, extravasation of plasma into intercellular spaces and accumulation of white blood cells and macrophages.</td><td valign="top">5.02E-04</td><td valign="top">AXL, CD55, HAS2, ITGB3, EMP3, IRF7, TNFRSF1B, NFKBIA, EDN1, DCBLD2, ATP2B1, CCL2, SRI, IL18, BST2, ADORA2B, CSF1, TNFAIP6, ADM, ITGA5, CCL7, TLR2, TPBG, HIF1A, PDPN, TAPBP, ABI1, KLF6, NFKB1, SERPINE1, GNAI3, RHOG, CCRL2, SLC7A1, ABCA1, SLC4A4, CDKN1A, GPC3, PVR, PLAUR, IFNGR2, IL18R1, RELA, IL6, P2RY2, EIF2AK2, TIMP1, MMP14, GCH1, LIF, CXCL10, KIF1B</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">HALLMARK_UV_ <break/>RESPONSE_DN</td><td valign="top">Genes down-regulated in response to ultraviolet (UV) radiation.</td><td valign="top">0.00149668</td><td valign="top">TGFBR2, EFEMP1, CYR61, FYN, CDON, HAS2, LAMC1, ANXA4, ITGB3, MGLL, ANXA2, PMP22, COL1A1, APBB2, ATP2B1, VLDLR, SRI, NR3C1, FBLN5, ADORA2B, COL1A2, COL3A1, PDLIM5, FZD2, IGFBP5, DUSP1, ADD3, SMAD7, SYNE1, CITED2, TGFBR3, NOTCH2, NFKB1, SERPINE1, ATRX, SDC2, SLC7A1, IGF1R, VAV2, CDKN1B, NEK7</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">HALLMARK_ <break/>COAGULATION</td><td valign="top">Genes encoding components of blood coagulation system; also up-regulated in platelets.</td><td valign="top">0.00112251</td><td valign="top">FN1, FBN1, PRSS23, DPP4, S100A13, FYN, BMP1, ANXA1, ITGB3, GDA, SPARC, CD9, PLAT, RAC1, ARF4, WDR1, CAPN2, ADAM9, SERPINE1, PECAM1, MAFF, DUSP14, KLF7, GNB2, HMGCS2, GNG12, TIMP1, TIMP3, MMP14</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">HALLMARK_TGF_ <break/>BETA_SIGNALING</td><td valign="top">Genes up-regulated in response to TGFB1.</td><td valign="top">8.98E-04</td><td valign="top">RHOA, SPTBN1, FKBP1A, BMP2, SKIL, SMURF2, CTNNB1, SMURF1, CDKN1C, SKI, SMAD7, BMPR2, SERPINE1, TGFBR1, ID3, IFNGR2, SMAD1, ACVR1, KLF10</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">HALLMARK_EPITHELIAL_ <break/>MESENCHYMAL_TRANSITION</td><td valign="top">Genes defining epithelial-mesenchymal transition, as in wound healing, fibrosis and metastasis.</td><td valign="top">7.48E-04</td><td valign="top">FN1, PCOLCE2, MFAP5, FBN1, FSTL1, LOXL1, CYR61, BMP1, THY1, LAMC1, ITGB3, EMP3, ECM1, SFRP4, DPYSL3, LOXL2, TPM4, SPARC, CAPG, CALU, LGALS1, PMP22, BASP1, TNFRSF11B, COL1A1, ITGB5, POSTN, FGF2, ANPEP, FLNA, PRRX1, CXCL1, EFEMP2, THBS2, TPM1, ITGAV, PPIB, TNFRSF12A, PDLIM4, SAT1, FBLN5, COL1A2, PTHLH, DST, LAMC2, COL3A1, IGFBP4, TPM2, ITGA5, COL16A1, ITGB1, WIPF1, FBN2, CALD1, PFN2, FZD8, TGFBR3, NOTCH2, SERPINE1, COL12A1</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">HALLMARK_APICAL_ <break/>JUNCTION</td><td valign="top">Genes encoding components of apical junction complex.</td><td valign="top">7.89E-04</td><td valign="top">FBN1, CD34, ACTG1, ADRA1B, THBS3, BMP1, THY1, MYH10, SIRPA, ZYX, CNN2, FLNC, TNFRSF11B, ARPC2, YWHAH, EPB41L2, LIMA1, MSN, ITGA9, PFN1, ACTB, VCL, PVRL3, RSU1, LAMC2, PARVA, COL16A1, ITGB1, PVRL1, CTNNA1, ADAM9, ADAM15, GAMT, PECAM1, PVRL4, CD276, VAV2, RRAS</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">HALLMARK_ALLOGRAFT_ <break/>REJECTION</td><td valign="top">Genes up-regulated during transplant rejection.</td><td valign="top">9.30E-04</td><td valign="top">CD47, THY1, RPL39, TGFB2, IRF7, CAPG, RPS9, FLNA, B2M, RPS19, CCL2, RPL9, CSK, GALNT1, IL18, CSF1, CCND3, INHBB, CCL7, TLR2, HIF1A, TAPBP, ELF4, IRF4, ABI1, PSMB10, CD80, IFNGR2, IL6, NPM1, UBE2D1, TIMP1</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">HALLMARK_APICAL_ <break/>SURFACE</td><td valign="top">Genes encoding proteins over-represented on the apical surface of epithelial cells, e.g., important for cell polarity (apical area).</td><td valign="top">0.002962323</td><td valign="top">SULF2, THY1, HSPB1, DCBLD2, EFNA5, ADAM10, PLAUR, ATP8B1</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">HALLMARK_MITOTIC_ <break/>SPINDLE</td><td valign="top">Genes important for mitotic spindle assembly.</td><td valign="top">0.002666091</td><td valign="top">MARCKS, FLNB, MYH10, TRIO, SPTBN1, FLNA, EPB41L2, SPTAN1, MAPRE1, RALBP1, CAPZB, ARHGAP29, ABL1, VCL, NIN, DST, ARF6, PDLIM5, CLASP1, YWHAE, KIFAP3, PXN, LMNB1, ARHGDIA, ABI1, NOTCH2, BIN1, DOCK4, KIF5B, PKD2, MYO1E, HOOK3, FARP1, WASF2, DYNC1H1, PREX1, MYH9, CKAP5, SMC3, SOS1, ITSN1, DYNLL2, CDK5RAP2, SMC1A, ARHGEF3, ESPL1, KIF1B, NEDD9, TIAM1, PPP4R2, ROCK1, PALLD, CD2AP, WASF1, CDC42BPA, RASA2, CDC42EP2, RHOT2, ALMS1, APC, PCM1, CDC27</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">HALLMARK_ <break/>COMPLEMENT</td><td valign="top">Genes encoding components of the complement system, which is part of the innate immune system.</td><td valign="top">0.003505879</td><td valign="top">FN1, DPP4, CD55, TIMP2, ATOX1, S100A13, GNGT2, FYN, KIF2A, IRF7, PLA2G4A, PLAT, CXCL1, CALM1, EHD1, PFN1, ADAM9, IRF2, SERPINE1, GNAI3, RHOG, PRCP, MAFF, GCA, DOCK4, PLAUR, GNB2, IL6, CEBPB, TIMP1, GNAI2, XPNPEP1, MMP14</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">HALLMARK_PROTEIN_ <break/>SECRETION</td><td valign="top">Genes involved in protein secretion pathway.</td><td valign="top">0.004820185</td><td valign="top">GNAS, PAM, ATP1A1, CLTA, ADAM10, DST, AP2B1, VAMP3, SSPN, RPS6KA3, MAPK1, SCRN1, AP3S1, ARFGAP3, SOD1, ABCA1, AP2S1, COPE, SNX2, ARFIP1, AP2M1, ARCN1, COPB1, ANP32E, LMAN1, CLTC, ERGIC3, DNM1L, RAB22A, TMED10, KIF1B, BET1, RAB14, COPB2, TSG101, AP3B1, STX12, GOLGA4, VPS4B, ARF1, MON2, RER1</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">HALLMARK_TNFA_ <break/>SIGNALING_VIA_NFKB</td><td valign="top">Genes regulated by NF-kB in response to TNF.</td><td valign="top">0.008500786</td><td valign="top">GFPT2, NR4A1, MARCKS, CYR61, PTGS2, SPSB1, NFKBIA, NR4A3, NFE2L2, EDN1, FOSL2, KLF2, CXCL1, ATP2B1, EIF1, PLK2, CCL2, B4GALT5, BMP2, EHD1, CCNL1, IER3, IL18, SAT1, NFIL3, CSF1, TNFAIP6, PDLIM5, NR4A2, TLR2, DUSP1, TRIP10, JAG1, RELB, PER1, IER2, TUBB2A, IER5, CXCL2, KLF6, NFKB1, SERPINE1, CCRL2, NFKBIE, MAFF, ABCA1, CDKN1A, KLF4, PLAUR, CD80, NFKB2, IFNGR2, RELA, IL6, CEBPB, GEM, FOSL1, IFIT2, DNAJB4, KLF10, ETS2, DDX58, GCH1, LIF</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">HALLMARK_HYPOXIA</td><td valign="top">Genes up-regulated in response to low oxygen levels (hypoxia).</td><td valign="top">0.01474173</td><td valign="top">PRDX5, CYR61, AKAP12, EXT1, CSRP2, PLAC8, UGP2, NDRG1, PTRF, ANXA2, PRKCDBP, PAM, HAS1, FOSL2, VLDLR, SLC6A6, HS3ST1, NAGK, ERRFI1, NR3C1, IER3, NFIL3, ADORA2B, ADM, CDKN1C, DUSP1, TPBG, DTNA, TPST2, CITED2, HK1, WSB1, KLF6, SERPINE1, GAPDH, SDC2, MAFF, AMPD3, PFKP, CDKN1A, CTGF, GPC3, IDS, PLAUR, KLF7, CDKN1B, PGM1, IL6, SULT2B1, TES, XPNPEP1, MYH9, HK2</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>