<table-wrap xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="table2" position="float"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.39636.008</object-id><label>Table 2.</label><caption><title>Gene sets enriched in committed preadipocytes (Cluster 1B).</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th valign="top">Gene set name</th><th valign="top">Gene set <break/>description</th><th valign="top">FDR q-value</th><th valign="top">Enriched genes</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td valign="top">HALLMARK_MYC_ <break/>TARGETS_V2</td><td valign="top">A subgroup of genes <break/>regulated by MYC - version 2.</td><td valign="top">0</td><td valign="top">SRM, GNL3, NOLC1, HSPE1, NIP7, HSPD1, PA2G4, NPM1, CDK4, PPAN, MYBBP1A, RCL1, PUS1, PHB, WDR43, HK2, WDR74, SLC19A1, GRWD1, EXOSC5, PES1, PRMT3, DDX18, TMEM97, IMP4, UNG, UTP20, LAS1L, MPHOSPH10, PPRC1, NOC4L, TBRG4, BYSL, IPO4, TFB2M</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">HALLMARK_OXIDATIVE_ <break/>PHOSPHORYLATION</td><td valign="top">Genes encoding proteins <break/>involved in oxidative <break/>phosphorylation.</td><td valign="top">0</td><td valign="top">ATP5G1, NNT, COX8A, TIMM13, TIMM10, LDHA, CYCS, TOMM70A, UQCRQ, COX7C, CYC1, COX7A2, ATP5G2, TIMM50, ATP5E, NDUFA4, NDUFAB1, SLC25A5, ATP5L, SLC25A4, PHB2, ACAT1, ATP5J, ATP5C1, CS, NDUFB8, NDUFB2, GRPEL1, UQCRFS1, IDH3A, NDUFV2, COX5A, NDUFC2, MRPS15, NDUFB4, POR, ECHS1, ATP5B, MRPS12, COX7B, LDHB, COX4I1, ATP5D, MRPL15, COX6B1, UQCRH, MDH2, SLC25A3, TIMM9, ATP5G3, NDUFB5, PRDX3, NDUFA2, ATP5A1, MRPS30, ATP5H, NDUFA7, NDUFC1, COX5B, PDHB, ATP5F1, MAOB, BAX, NDUFA3, GPX4, NDUFS8, VDAC2, COX6C, POLR2F, NDUFS3, COX6A1, NDUFS2, UQCRB, TIMM17A, ACADM, NDUFS7, ATP5O, MRPL11, IDH1, MRPL35, SUCLG1, HCCS, SDHD, MRPL34, MRPS11, NDUFB7, VDAC1, ATP5J2, NDUFA8, GOT2, OXA1L, SLC25A11, NDUFS6, NDUFA6, ETFB, IMMT, HTRA2, MTRR, FXN, SDHB, ACO2, FDX1, NDUFB6, DLAT, PMPCA, DLD, IDH2, AFG3L2, ETFDH, MTX2, TIMM8B, RETSAT, COX7A2L, TOMM22, NDUFA5, SUCLA2, UQCRC1, ALDH6A1, RHOT1, ECH1, SURF1, ATP6V1G1, VDAC3, PDHX, LRPPRC, UQCRC2, HADHB</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">HALLMARK_ <break/>ADIPOGENESIS</td><td valign="top">Genes up-regulated <break/>during adipocyte <break/>differentiation (adipogenesis).</td><td valign="top">0</td><td valign="top">REEP6, COL15A1, MYLK, APOE, COX8A, PIM3, CMBL, UQCRQ, LPL, SLC1A5, CYC1, PPARG, NDUFAB1, TKT, YWHAG, CS, DBT, GRPEL1, IDH3A, SCP2, SLC25A10, POR, ECHS1, FZD4, G3BP2, COX7B, SLC19A1, AK2, MRPL15, JAGN1, ENPP2, MDH2, ALDOA, PRDX3, MRAP, RAB34, DDT, MTCH2, HADH, PTGER3, LIPE, CPT2, REEP5, MCCC1, ANGPT1, GPX4, AGPAT3, NDUFS3, COX6A1, TANK, ACADM, SCARB1, ATP5O, ADCY6, GPX3, IDH1, SUCLG1, PEX14, SPARCL1, SDPR, PREB, GHITM, ALDH2, ADIPOR2, NDUFB7, EPHX2, ACADS, DNAJC15, GPHN, HIBCH, FAM73B, CHUK, VEGFB, ETFB, IMMT, ACOX1, RREB1, QDPR, FABP4, ACLY, ELOVL6, SDHB, PFKL, ACO2, RETN, CAT, PTCD3, DLAT, DLD, TST, CD36, DHRS7B, ITSN1, RETSAT, NDUFA5, UQCRC1, UBQLN1, DNAJB9, ECH1, SLC27A1</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">HALLMARK_MYC_ <break/>TARGETS_V1</td><td valign="top">A subgroup of genes <break/>regulated by <break/>MYC - version 1 (v1).</td><td valign="top">0</td><td valign="top">RPLP0, SRM, RPL6, GNL3, RPS2, RPL18, CNBP, RPS5, APEX1, RPL14, RPS6, RANBP1, SERBP1, ERH, C1QBP, RPL34, NOLC1, HSPE1, GNB2L1, HSPD1, PABPC1, SET, LDHA, EIF4A1, RPS3, PA2G4, SNRPD1, RSL1D1, TOMM70A, RAN, DDX21, NPM1, EIF2S2, CYC1, PABPC4, CDK4, IMPDH2, FBL, NAP1L1, NDUFAB1, RPL22, ABCE1, PHB2, HDGF, SNRPD2, LSM7, RPS10, HSP90AB1, PHB, CCT2, PPM1G, SNRPD3, SYNCRIP, PCBP1, CCT3, LSM2, EPRS, NME1, EIF2S1, GSPT1, COX5A, CCT7, CCT5, TUFM, U2AF1, PPIA, TCP1, ODC1, POLE3, ACP1, EEF1B2, TARDBP, YWHAE, SLC25A3, EIF1AX, SNRPA1, ETF1, SRPK1, PSMD7, PRDX3, SMARCC1, RAD23B, CCT4, RNPS1, FAM120A, RUVBL2, TXNL4A, EIF4E, KARS, PTGES3, GLO1, DDX18, MCM7, HDAC2, CANX, DUT, PRPF31, UBE2L3, KPNB1, NCBP1, SNRPA, POLD2, PSMA7, EIF4G2, PSMB2, PRPS2, DHX15, SSBP1, CLNS1A, PSMB3, PGK1, XPOT, STARD7, H2AFZ, ILF2, VDAC1, SSB, CTPS, GOT2, MRPS18B, SNRPG, COPS5, MRPL9, PSMA2, CAD, PSMA4, TRIM28, IARS, SF3B3, PSMD14, SNRPB2, UBE2E1, NCBP2, PWP1, YWHAQ, PSMD8, AP3S1, RFC4, HDDC2, PSMA6, XPO1, VDAC3, PSMC4, CDK2, USP1, MYC, PCNA, MRPL23</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">HALLMARK_ <break/>DNA_REPAIR</td><td valign="top">Genes involved <break/>in DNA repair.</td><td valign="top">0.001391793</td><td valign="top">AK1, TMED2, BOLA2, IMPDH2, POLR1D, SAC3D1, APRT, NUDT9, NME1, NUDT21, SSRP1, RAE1, ADRM1, GTF2A2, GUK1, POLR2D, GTF2H5, GPX4, POLR2F, MPG, DUT, SEC61A1, ADCY6, POLR2E, POLE4, RBX1, NT5C3, POLR1C, AK3, POLR2C, TAF10, GTF2H1, RNMT, DDB1, NME4, NFX1, POLR3GL, EIF1B, POLR2G, NCBP2, POLR2K, POLR2H, SURF1, ERCC8, TSG101, RFC4, RFC5, PCNA, UPF3B, POLR2I, RAD51, ITPA, EDF1, PRIM1, DAD1, TAF12, GTF2F1, POLD3, TCEB3, DCTN4, ARL6IP1, POLA1</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">HALLMARK_ <break/>MTORC1_SIGNALING</td><td valign="top">Genes up-regulated through <break/>activation of mTORC1 complex.</td><td valign="top">0.001159828</td><td valign="top">PSAT1, ATP5G1, HSPE1, HSPD1, LDHA, TOMM40, SLC1A5, EIF2S2, ENO1, EEF1E1, PHGDH, ARPC5L, SQLE, EPRS, HSPA4, PPIA, PSME3, HK2, GAPDH, MTHFD2, ETF1, ALDOA, PDAP1, PPA1, XBP1, ABCF2, BCAT1, UBE2D3, CACYBP, CYB5B, PSMA3, SLC7A5, TXNRD1, CANX, INSIG1, TMEM97, IDH1, HMBS, SSR1, PSMB5, ADIPOR2, PGK1, SERPINH1, UNG, PLOD2, PSPH, PRDX1, POLR3G, RPN1, DAPP1, IMMT, SLC2A1, QDPR, ACLY, ELOVL6, ATP2A2, PFKL, GTF2H1, COPS5, LDLR, SHMT2, UFM1, PSMA4, FDXR, TCEA1, GMPS, IDI1, PSMD12, ELOVL5, PSMD14, MAP2K3, PITPNB, MLLT11, TPI1, GSK3B, M6PR, PSMC4, ME1, NUP205, SLC2A3, NUFIP1, GSR, UCHL5, HMGCR</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">HALLMARK_FATTY_ <break/>ACID_METABOLISM</td><td valign="top">Genes encoding proteins <break/>involved in metabolism <break/>of fatty acids.</td><td valign="top">0.00329518</td><td valign="top">REEP6, MIF, APEX1, LDHA, AOC3, FASN, SUCLG2, ECHS1, ODC1, MDH2, ALDOA, HADH, PDHB, BCKDHB, CPT2, ACADM, SETD8, ADSL, IDH1, SUCLG1, HCCS, SDHD, ADIPOR2, ERP29, H2AFZ, ACADS, HIBCH, PRDX6, ACOX1, GSTZ1, ACO2, GRHPR, G0S2, DLD, CD36, ACSL1, IDI1, ELOVL5, ETFDH, CCDC58, RETSAT, METAP1, SUCLA2, ECH1, HSP90AA1, HSPH1, MCEE, HADHB, ME1, GCDH, IDH3B, CRAT, SDHC, MLYCD, AQP7, DLST, HSD17B7, HMGCS1, SMS, GPD1, RDH11, ACADVL, NSDHL, HMGCL, DECR1, ACSL5, UROS</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">HALLMARK_ <break/>PEROXISOME</td><td valign="top">Genes annotated by the <break/>GO term GO:0005777. A small, <break/>membrane-bounded organelle <break/>that uses dioxygen (O2) to <break/>oxidize organic molecules; <break/>contains some enzymes that <break/>produce and others that degrade <break/>hydrogen peroxide (H2O2).</td><td valign="top">0.002883282</td><td valign="top">CNBP, PABPC1, SLC25A4, SCP2, SMARCC1, PEX11A, FDPS, SLC35B2, SOD2, IDH1, PEX14, EPHX2, CTPS, GNPAT, PRDX1, PEX13, NUDT19, ACOX1, CTBP1, CAT, IDH2, ACSL1, IDI1, ELOVL5, RETSAT, ECH1, ABCD3, SLC25A17, PEX5, CDK7, CRAT, MLYCD, PEX11B, HRAS, DHRS3, ISOC1, RDH11, ABCD2, HMGCL, ACSL5, SLC23A2, SOD1, TOP2A, CRABP1</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">HALLMARK_ <break/>E2F_TARGETS</td><td valign="top">Genes encoding cell cycle related <break/>targets of E2F transcription factors.</td><td valign="top">0.004273379</td><td valign="top">RANBP1, NOLC1, CKS1B, PA2G4, RAN, LYAR, CDK4, NAP1L1, SYNCRIP, NME1, EIF2S1, GSPT1, PHF5A, MTHFD2, AK2, NUDT21, SSRP1, SNRPB, TIPIN, UBE2S, IPO7, PNN, MCM7, SHMT1, DUT, H2AFX, NUP153, HN1, POLD2, POLE4, HMGB3, H2AFZ, UNG, CTPS, HELLS, PAICS, CENPM, ILF3, RBBP7, PSIP1, RAD1, TBRG4, NASP, PRPS1, PSMC3IP, TK1, BRMS1L, RAD51AP1, CDKN2A, CTCF, RAD50, POP7, XPO1, TCF19, ASF1A, CDKN2C, USP1, NUP205, MYC, PCNA, POLE, PPP1R8, ASF1B, SMC1A, ATAD2, DIAPH3, MCM5, CCNB2, DEK, RFC1, XRCC6, BRCA2, CSE1L, EZH2, ANP32E, POLD3, MCM2, SMC6, MCM6, RQCD1, DONSON, ZW10, CKS2, BRCA1, MRE11A, RPA3, KIF22, PLK4, BIRC5, CDC25A, GINS1, CDCA3, KPNA2, HMMR, SMC4, CCNE1, MXD3, EXOSC8, RFC2, MLH1, TRIP13, TOP2A, MAD2L1</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">HALLMARK_ <break/>UNFOLDED_ <break/>PROTEIN_RESPONSE</td><td valign="top">Genes up-regulated during <break/>unfolded protein response, a <break/>cellular stress response related <break/>to the endoplasmic reticulum.</td><td valign="top">0.005032035</td><td valign="top">PSAT1, RPS14, NOLC1, CKS1B, EIF4A1, EEF2, NPM1, DKC1, LSM4, EIF4EBP1, EIF2S1, EXOSC1, MTHFD2, SDAD1, XBP1, EXOSC5, EIF4E, EIF4G1, SLC7A5, EXOSC2, H2AFX, CEBPG, SSR1, PREB, XPOT, BANF1, DDX10, EXOSC4, FUS, PARN, TARS, LSM1, SRPRB, IARS, SPCS1, DNAJB9, BAG3, EIF4A2</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">HALLMARK_G2M_ <break/>CHECKPOINT</td><td valign="top">Genes involved in the G2/M <break/>checkpoint, as in progression <break/>through the cell division cycle.</td><td valign="top">0.005412505</td><td valign="top">NCL, NOLC1, CKS1B, SNRPD1, CDK4, DKC1, DTYMK, UCK2, SYNCRIP, SQLE, GSPT1, HSPA8, ODC1, EWSR1, SMARCC1, RAD23B, HMGN2, UBE2S, PRPF4B, DR1, PRMT5, AMD1, SLC7A5, SETD8, H2AFX, HN1, KPNB1, HMGB3, SFPQ, H2AFZ, ILF3, TNPO2, SLC7A1, TOP1, NASP, CBX1, NUP50, CASP8AP2, E2F4, CTCF, XPO1, CDKN2C, MYC, CUL4A, POLE, CCNT1, YTHDC1, SMC1A, MCM5, CCNB2, BRCA2, CASC5, KATNA1, POLQ, EZH2, CUL1, MCM2, ODF2, MTF2, MCM6, WHSC1, NEK2, E2F1, SMC2, SS18, CKS2, E2F3, KIF22, PLK4, HIF1A, EXO1, BIRC5, H2AFV, CDC25A, KPNA2, CHAF1A, PAFAH1B1, HMMR, SMC4, PBK, TROAP, GINS2, CENPF, CCNA2, RBM14, TOP2A, MAD2L1, KIF11, STMN1, BUB3, DBF4, RPA2, TPX2, RBL1, BARD1, UPF1, CENPE, ATRX, KIF5B, HIRA, PRC1, CCND1, CDC27, CHEK1, CENPA, SUV39H1, MNAT1, STIL, POLA2, TFDP1, FBXO5, PURA, MKI67, AURKA, UBE2C, EGF, CDC25B, ZAK, TMPO, CUL5, MCM3, WRN, MYBL2, RAD54L, LIG3, TTK, SMAD3, RACGAP1</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">HALLMARK_REACTIVE_ <break/>OXIGEN_SPECIES_ <break/>PATHWAY</td><td valign="top">Genes up-regulated by <break/>reactive oxigen species (ROS).</td><td valign="top">0.011108679</td><td valign="top">MGST1, NDUFB4, SOD2, GPX4, TXNRD1, NDUFS2, GPX3, PRDX2, PRDX6, PRDX1, NDUFA6, PPP2R4, CAT, MSRA, GLRX2</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">HALLMARK_PI3K_ <break/>AKT_MTOR_ <break/>SIGNALING</td><td valign="top">Genes up-regulated by <break/>activation of the <break/>PI3K/AKT/mTOR pathway.</td><td valign="top">0.012494773</td><td valign="top">PLA2G12A, PTEN, CDK4, PRKAR2A, PPP1CA, PFN1, PIN1, UBE2D3, EIF4E, PLCB1, UBE2N, AKT1S1, AKT1, RPS6KA3, TNFRSF1A, DAPP1, SLC2A1, YWHAB, PPP2R1B, MKNK2, CFL1, ECSIT, MAPKAP1, MAP2K3, PLCG1, ATF1, GSK3B, RAF1, CDK2, MAP3K7, ARHGDIA, HRAS, CAB39L, RIPK1, E2F1, CALR, AP2M1, MYD88, CSNK2B, ARF1, PTPN11, PAK4, SMAD2</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">HALLMARK_ <break/>XENOBIOTIC_ <break/>METABOLISM</td><td valign="top">Genes encoding proteins <break/>involved in processing of <break/>drugs and other xenobiotics.</td><td valign="top">0.018676866</td><td valign="top">IGF1, APOE, CSAD, SLC1A5, GSTO1, RBP4, PMM1, POR, ENPEP, ACP1, NDRG2, DDT, BCAT1, KARS, PTGES3, IL1R1, TMEM97, IDH1, PTGES, ALDH2, MCCC2, TNFRSF1A, ACOX1, MTHFD1, ATP2A2, TPST1, PGD, ACO2, CAT, SHMT2, IGFBP4, GART, CD36, ELOVL5, ETFDH, RETSAT, SSR3, ADH5, DDAH2, ECH1</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>