<table-wrap xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="table5" position="float"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.35856.024</object-id><label>Table 5.</label><caption><title>Key findings from cluster analysis</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><tbody><tr><td valign="top">Certain childhood populations may be broadly split into three clusters, each representing a&#160;unique trajectory of immune function and susceptibility to respiratory infections: low-risk non-&#160;atopic Cluster 1 with transient wheeze; low-risk but allergy-susceptible Cluster 2 with&#160;mixed wheeze; and strongly-atopic high-risk Cluster 3 with persistent wheeze.</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Cluster 3 is consistent with an early-sensitised and multi-sensitised phenotype.</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">HDM hypersensitivity is an important predictor of wheeze in allergic or allergy -susceptible&#160;individuals.</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Food and peanut hypersensitivities are important contributors to membership in high-risk Cluster&#160;3. This may be pathophysiologically related to eczema, multi-sensitisation and the atopic march.</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">In CAS, IgG4 flags for clusters with susceptibility to atopic disease (CAS2 and CAS3), while early and&#160;multiple-allergen elevation in IgE predicts frank atopic disease. The pathophysiological role of IgG4&#160;remains unclear.</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Allergic and infective processes act additively to intensify airway inflammation during respiratory&#160;pathogen clearance. Some (Cluster 3) may be more susceptible to this effect than others that lack&#160;strong allergic sensitisation (Cluster 1).</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Tests for atopy (IgE, SPT, cytokines) do not overlap perfectly. Therefore, atopy may be better&#160;defined by the composite result from a battery of tests encapsulated in a predictive model, rather&#160;than just a single test or threshold.</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">The microbiome acts differently on asthma risk depending on cluster membership. In CAS, early-life asymptomatic colonisation with infection-associated MPGs is associated with risk of persistent&#160;wheeze in allergy-susceptible clusters (CAS2, CAS3), while it is potentially protective in non-atopic&#160;children (CAS1)</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Different childhood populations may share similar trajectories of asthma susceptibility, but there&#160;may be subtle differences in terms of the types of tests, allergens, or biological signals that are most&#160;informative (SPT, IgE, cytokines, etc.).</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>