<table-wrap xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="tbl1" position="float"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.06369.014</object-id><label>Table 1.</label><caption><p>Dietary sources of ascorbate in animal auxotrophs</p><p><bold>DOI:</bold> <ext-link ext-link-type="doi" xlink:href="10.7554/eLife.06369.014">http://dx.doi.org/10.7554/eLife.06369.014</ext-link></p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th>Animal auxotroph</th><th>Primary dietary source of ascorbate</th><th>Ultimate dietary source of ascorbate</th><th>Enzyme for ascorbate synthesis</th><th>References</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Primates</td><td>Land plants</td><td/><td>GLDH</td><td>(<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib67">Milton and Jenness, 1987</xref>)</td></tr><tr><td>Guinea pig</td><td>Land plants</td><td/><td>GLDH</td><td/></tr><tr><td rowspan="4">Bats</td><td>Land plants</td><td/><td>GLDH</td><td rowspan="4">(<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib6">Birney et al., 1976</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib67">Milton and Jenness, 1987</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib14">Cui et al., 2011b</xref>)</td></tr><tr><td>Insects</td><td>Land plants</td><td>GLDH</td></tr><tr><td>Fish</td><td>Phytoplankton</td><td>GLDH</td></tr><tr><td>Blood</td><td/><td>GULO</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="3">Passerine birds</td><td>Land plants</td><td/><td>GLDH</td><td rowspan="3">(<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib22">Drouin et al., 2011</xref>)</td></tr><tr><td>Insects</td><td>Land plants</td><td>GLDH</td></tr><tr><td>Small vertebrates</td><td/><td>GULO</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="2">Teleost fish</td><td>Zooplankton (crustacea)</td><td>Phytoplankton</td><td>GLDH</td><td rowspan="2">(<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib16">Dabrowski, 1990</xref>)</td></tr><tr><td>Phytoplankton</td><td/><td>GLDH</td></tr><tr><td>Crustacea</td><td>Phytoplankton</td><td/><td>GLDH</td><td>(<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib19">Desjardins et al., 1985</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib30">Hapette and Poulet, 1990</xref>)</td></tr><tr><td>Phytophagous insects</td><td>Land plants</td><td/><td>GLDH</td><td>(<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib76">Pierre, 1962</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib17">Dadd, 1973</xref>)</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn><p>Major sources of dietary ascorbate were identified in known animal auxotrophs. This information allows us to assess which terminal enzyme contributed to the production of dietary ascorbate. In nearly all cases the major source of dietary ascorbate is most likely to have been derived from GLDH. Phylogenetic analyses suggest GULO has been lost on multiple independent occasions throughout the Chiroptera (bats). Although ancestral bats may have been primarily insectivores, various sources of dietary ascorbate may have contributed to GULO loss. The passerine birds that are unable to synthesise ascorbate are primarily herbivores or insectivores. However, some members of the <italic>Lanius</italic> genus (shrikes) feed also on small vertebrates, in addition to insects. Most teleost fish are believed to be ascorbate auxotrophs due to loss of GULO. As zooplankton (primarily crustacea) are also ascorbate auxtrophs, phytoplankton are likely to be the ultimate source of dietary ascorbate. Reports suggest the ability of crustacea to synthesise ascorbate is either absent or very weak, although the taxonomic sampling and currently available genomic resources are limited. Most, but not all, phytophagous insects have a dietary requirement for ascorbate, and we did not find GULO in any insect genomes. Note also that some species of insect (e.g., cockroaches) may obtain ascorbate from eukaryote endosymbionts, which may allow them to survive on ascorbate-poor diets.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap>