<table-wrap xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="tbl1" position="float"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.18855.018</object-id><label>Table 1.</label><caption><p>Summary of volatiles detected using GC-MS. Relative abundance of volatiles in the co-culture (<italic>S. cerevisiae</italic> and <italic>A. malorum</italic> grown together) compared to the separate-culture mixture (<italic>S. cerevisiae</italic> and <italic>A. malorum</italic> grown separately, and their quantities added in during analysis). GC-MS captured volatiles with XAD-4 beads suspended above the cultures during growth; subsequently, beads were methanol-extracted (n&#160;=&#160;6 experiments, <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SD10-data">Table 1&#8212;source data 1</xref>&#8211;<xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SD11-data">2</xref>). Quantification is based on two experiments in which a linear regression was computed with standards (<xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SD12-data">Table 1&#8212;source data 3</xref>&#8211;<xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SD13-data">4</xref>). Quantification is based on beads suspended above the cultures between 84 and 96 hr of culture growth.</p><p><bold>DOI:</bold> <ext-link ext-link-type="doi" xlink:href="10.7554/eLife.18855.018">http://dx.doi.org/10.7554/eLife.18855.018</ext-link></p><p><supplementary-material id="SD10-data"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.18855.019</object-id><label>Table 1&#8212;source data 1.</label><caption><title>Extracted ion chromatograms of five metabolites detected by gas chromatography-mass spectrometry (GC-MS) in <xref ref-type="table" rid="tbl1">Table 1</xref>.</title><p>Extracted ion chromatograms of the five metabolites detected by gas chromatography- mass spectrometry (GC-MS). (A) Schematic depicting the experimental setup (B-F) Representative extracted ion chromatograms from one replicate (out of three total) of one experiment (out of 3&#8211;4 total) of m/z values corresponding to major metabolites identified in the experimental conditions along with appropriate standards. Acetic acid (B), isoamyl alcohol (C), isoamyl acetate (D) isobutanol (E), and ethanol (F) were identified as the five major metabolites in the co-culture (<italic>S. cerevisiae</italic> and <italic>A. malorum</italic>). Isoamyl alcohol (C), ethanol (E), and isobutanol (F) were identified as the major metabolites in <italic>S. cerevisiae</italic> grown alone. Extracted ion chromatograms were constructed using the m/z value in the title of each graph. For acetic acid and isobutanol, the m/z value used corresponds to the molecular weight of the molecule. For ethanol, the m/z used corresponds to the molecular weight minus one (hydrogen). For isoamyl alcohol, the m/z used corresponds to the loss of the hydroxyl group (depicted), which may have picked up hydrogen and been lost as water. For isoamyl acetate, the m/z value corresponds to the molecule shown within the graph. In all cases, figures showing the complete mass spectra between the metabolite and standard are found in <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SD11-data">Table 1&#8212;source data 2</xref>. Microorganisms were grown 72&#8211;96 hr.</p><p><bold>DOI:</bold> <ext-link ext-link-type="doi" xlink:href="10.7554/eLife.18855.019">http://dx.doi.org/10.7554/eLife.18855.019</ext-link></p></caption><media mime-subtype="pdf" mimetype="application" xlink:href="elife-18855-table1-data1-v2.pdf"/></supplementary-material></p><p><supplementary-material id="SD11-data"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.18855.020</object-id><label>Table 1&#8212;source data 2.</label><caption><title>Representative spectra of metabolites in <xref ref-type="table" rid="tbl1">Table 1</xref>.</title><p>Representative spectra of acetic acid (A-B), isoamyl alcohol (C-E), isoamyl acetate (F-G), ethanol (H-J) and isobutanol (K-L) in standard and experimental samples. Standard concentrations are denoted on individual graphs. All mass spectra are one replicate (out of 3&#8211;4 experiments with three replicates per experiment).</p><p><bold>DOI:</bold> <ext-link ext-link-type="doi" xlink:href="10.7554/eLife.18855.020">http://dx.doi.org/10.7554/eLife.18855.020</ext-link></p></caption><media mime-subtype="pdf" mimetype="application" xlink:href="elife-18855-table1-data2-v2.pdf"/></supplementary-material></p><p><supplementary-material id="SD12-data"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.18855.021</object-id><label>Table 1&#8212;source data 3.</label><caption><title>Linear regression of metabolites using GC-MS in <xref ref-type="table" rid="tbl1">Table 1</xref>.</title><p>Estimation of volatile quantity using GC-MS. Separate experiments are graphed in panels (A-E) and (F-J). (A-E) Data points represent the value of a single replicate per concentration for each standard. The abundance of a single m/z value at a specific retention time was chosen for each standard. The values were fitted with a linear regression and the equation was used to estimate the concentration of the five metabolites in the experimental samples from the same experiment. (F-J) Data points represent the mean &#177; SEM of three replicates for a given concentration for each standard. The abundance of a single m/z value at a specific retention time was chosen for each standard. The values were fitted with a linear regression. The equation was used to estimate the concentration of the five metabolites in the experimental samples from the same experiment. When applicable an equation was calculated when the line was forced to go through X,Y&#160;=&#160;0,0; these equations were used to calculate the concentrations of isoamyl alcohol, isoamyl acetate, and isobutanol.</p><p><bold>DOI:</bold> <ext-link ext-link-type="doi" xlink:href="10.7554/eLife.18855.021">http://dx.doi.org/10.7554/eLife.18855.021</ext-link></p></caption><media mime-subtype="pdf" mimetype="application" xlink:href="elife-18855-table1-data3-v2.pdf"/></supplementary-material></p><p><supplementary-material id="SD13-data"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.18855.022</object-id><label>Table 1&#8212;source data 4.</label><caption><title>Raw spectral abundance data as a function of concentration used for linear regressions in <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SD12-data">Table 1&#8212;source data 3</xref>.</title><p><bold>DOI:</bold> <ext-link ext-link-type="doi" xlink:href="10.7554/eLife.18855.022">http://dx.doi.org/10.7554/eLife.18855.022</ext-link></p></caption><media mime-subtype="xlsx" mimetype="application" xlink:href="elife-18855-table1-data4-v2.xlsx"/></supplementary-material></p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th><p>Identity</p></th><th><p>Standard confirmation</p></th><th><p>Relative quantification (co-culture: separate-culture mixture)</p></th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><p>Ethanol</p></td><td><p>Y</p></td><td><p>5.0&#8211;12.6-fold reduced</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Isobutanol</p></td><td><p>Y</p></td><td><p>7.3&#8211;24.7-fold reduced</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Isoamyl acetate</p></td><td><p>Y</p></td><td><p>unique to co-culture</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Isoamyl alcohol</p></td><td><p>Y</p></td><td><p>3.6&#8211;6.4-fold reduced</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Acetic acid</p></td><td><p>Y</p></td><td><p>unique to co-culture</p></td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>