<table-wrap xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="table1" position="float"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.40042.004</object-id><label>Table 1.</label><caption><title>Past and present summary of historical tract-tracing studies in macaque and marmoset monkeys.</title><p>Three resources of macaque monkey brain connectivity are shown. Felleman and Van Essen (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib16">Felleman and Van Essen, 1991</xref>) and CoCoMac each surveyed a set of studies to generate the connectivity matrix (full reference list in <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="supp2">Supplementary file 2</xref>). Note that CoCoMac is inclusive of the work collected in Felleman and Van Essen (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib16">Felleman and Van Essen, 1991</xref>). Around 235 injections lack tracer direction information. <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib42">Markov et al. (2014)</xref> was a single study using only the retrograde tracer to generate the connectivity matrix as well as quantifying the connection strengths. We have surveyed 35 marmoset brain tracing studies that contain 428 tracer injections including both anterograde and retrograde tracers. A complete connectivity matrix is not yet available for the marmoset brain. To date, the most comprehensive marmoset brain connectivity resource available online (<ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://monash.marmoset.brainarchitecture.org">http://monash.marmoset.brainarchitecture.org</ext-link>) includes 143 retrograde tracing studies. As part of the current pipeline, we have placed over 188 tracer injections including both anterograde and retrograde tracers. For both macaque and marmoset brain injections, bidirectional tracer injections were double counted as one anterograde and one retrograde tracer injection.</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th valign="bottom"/><th valign="bottom">Data</th><th>Species</th><th>Injections</th><th>Anterograde tracer</th><th>Retrograde tracer</th><th>Connectivity matrix</th><th>Source</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td rowspan="4">Journal papers</td><td rowspan="4">No whole-brain image data</td><td rowspan="3">Macaque</td><td>370</td><td>153</td><td>217</td><td>33 &#215; 33</td><td><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib16">Felleman and Van Essen, 1991</xref> (52 studies)</td></tr><tr><td>3279</td><td>1429</td><td>1873</td><td>58 &#215; 58</td><td>CoCoMac (459 studies)</td></tr><tr><td>39</td><td>0</td><td>39</td><td>29 &#215; 91</td><td><xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib42">Markov et al., 2014</xref></td></tr><tr><td>Marmoset</td><td>428</td><td>93</td><td>395</td><td>-</td><td>35 studies (Bibliography in supplement)</td></tr><tr><td rowspan="2">Whole-brain image data</td><td>Nissl images overlaid with cell locations (Rosa Lab data set)</td><td rowspan="2">Marmoset</td><td>143</td><td>0</td><td>143</td><td>-</td><td>Online</td></tr><tr><td>This paper: Whole-brain set of cross-modal serial sections (Nissl,Myelin, IHC, Fluoro)+MRI</td><td>188</td><td>94</td><td>94</td><td>-</td><td>This paper</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>