<table-wrap xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="tbl1" position="float"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.01911.005</object-id><label>Table 1.</label><caption><p>Summary of the targeting rates obtained by sequence-based identification of locus-targeted indels after LP-directed delivery of ZFN proteins</p><p><bold>DOI:</bold> <ext-link ext-link-type="doi" xlink:href="10.7554/eLife.01911.005">http://dx.doi.org/10.7554/eLife.01911.005</ext-link></p><p><supplementary-material id="SD1-data"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.01911.006</object-id><label>Table 1&#8212;source data 1.</label><caption><title>Sequences of <italic>egfp</italic> gene disruption by ZFN protein transduction in the HEK293-eGFPmut reporter cells.</title><p>Genomic DNA of HEK293-eGFPmut reporter cells transduced with 600 ng p24 LP-ZFNLR(gfp) was used as PCR template for amplification and subsequent cloning of the part of the <italic>egfp</italic> gene encompassing the region recognized by the two ZFNs. The wild-type sequence is shown at the top. The net change of length caused by indels is indicated to the right of each sequence. Green dashes represent deleted nucleotides, red lower case letters represent nucleotide substitutions, whereas blue lower case letters illustrate inserted nucleotides. If one particular sequence appeared in more than one clone, the exact number of clones with this particular sequence is provided in parenthesis.</p><p><bold>DOI:</bold> <ext-link ext-link-type="doi" xlink:href="10.7554/eLife.01911.006">http://dx.doi.org/10.7554/eLife.01911.006</ext-link></p></caption><media mime-subtype="pdf" mimetype="application" xlink:href="elife-01911-data1-v2.pdf"/></supplementary-material></p><p><supplementary-material id="SD2-data"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.01911.007</object-id><label>Table 1&#8212;source data 2.</label><caption><title>Sequences of <italic>CCR5</italic> gene disruption by ZFN protein transduction of HEK293, NHDFs and HKs.</title><p>Genomic DNA of cells transduced with 200 ng p24 LP-ZFNLR(CCR5) was used as PCR template for amplification and subsequent cloning of a <italic>CCR5</italic> amplicon encompassing the region recognized by the two ZFNs. The wild-type sequence is shown at the top. Types of indels are indicated as described in the legend to <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SD1-data">Table 1&#8212;source data 1</xref>.</p><p><bold>DOI:</bold> <ext-link ext-link-type="doi" xlink:href="10.7554/eLife.01911.007">http://dx.doi.org/10.7554/eLife.01911.007</ext-link></p></caption><media mime-subtype="pdf" mimetype="application" xlink:href="elife-01911-data2-v2.pdf"/></supplementary-material></p><p><supplementary-material id="SD3-data"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.01911.008</object-id><label>Table 1&#8212;source data 3.</label><caption><title>Sequences of <italic>AAVS1</italic> gene disruption by ZFN protein transduction in HEK293, NHDFs and HKs.</title><p>Genomic DNA of cells transduced with 200 ng p24 LP-ZFNLR(AAVS1) was used as PCR template for amplification and subsequent cloning of an <italic>AAVS1</italic> amplicon encompassing the region recognized by the two ZFNs. The wild-type sequence is shown at the top. Types of indels are indicated as described in the legend to <xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SD1-data">Table 1&#8212;source data 1</xref>. If one particular sequence appeared in more than one clone, the exact number of clones with this sequence is provided in parenthesis.</p><p><bold>DOI:</bold> <ext-link ext-link-type="doi" xlink:href="10.7554/eLife.01911.008">http://dx.doi.org/10.7554/eLife.01911.008</ext-link></p></caption><media mime-subtype="pdf" mimetype="application" xlink:href="elife-01911-data3-v2.pdf"/></supplementary-material></p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th/><th colspan="3">Cell type</th></tr><tr><th>Target locus</th><th>HEK293</th><th>Normal human dermal fibroblasts</th><th>Primary human keratinocytes</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><italic>egfp</italic></td><td>8/42 (19%)<xref ref-type="table-fn" rid="tblfn1">*</xref></td><td>N/A</td><td>N/A</td></tr><tr><td><italic>CCR5</italic></td><td>7/42 (17%)</td><td>8/46 (17%)</td><td>11/45 (24%)</td></tr><tr><td><italic>AAVS1</italic></td><td>6/46 (13%)</td><td>7/43 (16%)</td><td>8/40 (20%)</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn><p>Provided ratios indicate the number of alleles with indels out of the total number of analyzed alleles after treatment with 600 ng p24 LP-ZFNLR(gfp), 200 ng p24 LP-ZFNLR(CCR5) or 200 ng p24 LP-ZFNLR(AAVS1), respectively.</p></fn><fn id="tblfn1"><label>*</label><p>indicates that data were obtained in HEK293-eGFPmut reporter cells; N/A, not available.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap>