<table-wrap xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="table2" position="float"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.50848.006</object-id><label>Table 2.</label><caption><title>Proposed spinal muscular atrophy (SMA)-microRNA relationships</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th valign="top">miRNA</th><th valign="top">Role in MN disease</th><th valign="top">Targets</th><th valign="top">Organism/cell models and expression profiles</th><th valign="top">Findings and proposed mechanism of SMA pathogenesis</th><th valign="top">References</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td valign="top"><italic>miR-2</italic></td><td valign="top">Neuronal development and function; correct NMJ functioning</td><td valign="top">CHRM2, m2R</td><td valign="top"><italic>C. elegans</italic> model, <break/>SMA mouse model. <break/>Decreased</td><td valign="top">Alters NMJ function</td><td valign="top">(<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib101">O'Hern et al., 2017</xref>)</td></tr><tr><td valign="top"><italic>miR-9&#160;</italic><sup>(1)</sup></td><td valign="top">MN dendritic outgrowth and synaptic function</td><td valign="top">Neurofilament heavy subunit (NEFH), REST, Map1b, MCPIP1</td><td valign="top">Mouse, patient fibroblasts, patient serum. <break/>Decreased in spinal cord, but increased in skeletal muscle</td><td valign="top">Dysregulated expression in MNs differentiated from ESCs. Regulation of MN subtype determination (FOXP1). <break/>miR-9 can delay neurite outgrowth in vitro and impair radial neuronal migration in embryonic mouse neocortex in vivo.</td><td valign="top">(<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib13">Catapano et al., 2016</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib49">Haramati et al., 2010</xref>)</td></tr><tr><td valign="top"><italic>miR-23a</italic></td><td valign="top">Neuroprotective properties; regulate axonal development; suppress skeletal muscle atrophy</td><td valign="top">Atrogin1, MuRF1 (maybe, no direct target experiment was verified by luciferase assay)</td><td valign="top">Patient induced pluripotent stem cells, <break/>SMA mouse model. <break/>Decreased</td><td valign="top"><italic>miR-23a</italic> can prevent the astrocyte-conditioned media-induced MN&#160;loss in vitro. <break/>In mice model, enhanced <italic>miR-23a</italic> expression via virus vector increased MN soma size and muscle fiber area, and reduced NMJ defects</td><td valign="top">(<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib62">Kaifer et al., 2019</xref>)</td></tr><tr><td valign="top"><italic>miR-100&#8211;5p</italic></td><td valign="top">Abnormal proliferation of neural progenitors; aberrant cell cycle</td><td valign="top">Potentially insulin-like growth factor one receptor (IGF1R)</td><td valign="top">SMN&#8710;7 mouse neural stem cells from spinal cord. <break/>Decreased</td><td valign="top">Decreased <italic>miR-100&#8211;5p</italic> in SMA&#916;7 mice neural stem cells induces high IGF1R, excessive proliferation of neural progenitors, and prevents appropriate exit of the cell cycle.</td><td valign="top">(<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib85">Luchetti et al., 2015</xref>)</td></tr><tr><td valign="top"><italic>miR-132</italic> (possible)</td><td valign="top">Neuron dendritic outgrowth and synaptic plasticity; neovascularization, may cause ischemic pathology in both skeletal muscle and spinal cord of SMA model</td><td valign="top">Dysregulated expression due to TDP43 interaction with Dicer (amyotrophic lateral sclerosis data), p250GAP</td><td valign="top">SMA mice, patient serum. <break/>Decreased in spinal cord, but increased in skeletal muscle</td><td valign="top">Expression is dysregulated in TDP-43-deficient amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS). <break/>Neuronal morphology and cognition in ALS. <break/><italic>miR-132</italic> can delay neurite outgrowth in vitro and impair radial neuronal migration in embryonic mouse neocortex in vivo. <break/>Involved in synaptic plasticity. <break/>Process of neovascularization. Recent reports have highlighted vascular defects in both skeletal muscle and spinal cord of SMA patients.</td><td valign="top">(<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib13">Catapano et al., 2016</xref>)</td></tr><tr><td valign="top"><italic>miR-146</italic></td><td valign="top">MN loss caused by astrocyte-mediated pathology through NF&#954;B signaling</td><td valign="top">GDNF, NOTCH2, GATA transcription factors</td><td valign="top">Patient induced pluripotent stem cells. <break/>Increased</td><td valign="top"><italic>miR-146</italic> levels are influenced both directly and indirectly by SMN1 levels. SMN re-expression decreases <italic>miR-146a</italic> levels nearly to control levels. <break/>The NF&#954;B pathway is an inducer of <italic>miR-146a</italic>.</td><td valign="top">(<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib111">Sison et al., 2017</xref>)</td></tr><tr><td valign="top"><italic>miR-183</italic></td><td valign="top">Protein synthesis; axonal outgrowth</td><td valign="top">mTOR pathway</td><td valign="top">Mouse, cortical neurons, patient fibroblasts. <break/>Increased</td><td valign="top">Increased <italic>miR-183</italic> and reduced local axonal translation of mTOR in SMN-deficient neurons.</td><td valign="top">(<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib70">Kye et al., 2014</xref>)</td></tr><tr><td valign="top"><italic>miR-206&#160;</italic><sup>(2)</sup> <break/>(muscle-specific)</td><td valign="top">Myofiber formation; satellite cell differentiation; neuroprotective role in re-innervation of muscle endplates after acute nerve injury</td><td valign="top">Axis of HDAC4-FGFBP1, <break/>Pola1, BDNF</td><td valign="top">SMA mouse, patient serum. <break/>Increased in both spinal cord and skeletal muscle</td><td valign="top">Endogenously increased <italic>miR-206</italic>, with HDAC4 protein reduction and increased <italic>FGFBP1</italic> mRNA, activates neuroprotective mechanism in muscle cells to increase re-innervation of muscle endplates.</td><td valign="top">(<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib13">Catapano et al., 2016</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib129">Valsecchi et al., 2015</xref>)</td></tr><tr><td valign="top"><italic>miR-335&#8211;5p</italic></td><td valign="top">Control of differentiation or self-renewal of mouse ESCs</td><td valign="top">MEST, OCT4, RB1</td><td valign="top">SMN&#8710;7 mouse neural stem cells, human induced pluripotent stem cells. <break/>Decreased</td><td valign="top">Possible epigenetic regulation through methylation to affect cell differentiation.</td><td valign="top">(<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib85">Luchetti et al., 2015</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib97">Murdocca et al., 2016</xref>)</td></tr><tr><td valign="top"><italic>miR-375</italic></td><td valign="top">Neurogenesis and protects neurons from apoptosis in response to DNA damage.</td><td valign="top">P53, PAX6, CCND2</td><td valign="top">Human neural progenitor cell cultures. <break/>Decreased</td><td valign="top">MNs from an SMA patient have shown reduced levels of <italic>miR-375</italic>, elevated p53 protein levels, and higher susceptibility to DNA damage-induced apoptosis.</td><td valign="top">(<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib10">Bhinge et al., 2016</xref>)</td></tr><tr><td valign="top"><italic>miR-431</italic></td><td valign="top">Regulation of motor neuron axon neurite outgrowth</td><td valign="top">Chondrolectin (Chodl): a type one transmembrane protein and member of the c-type lectin domain-containing family</td><td valign="top">Mouse MN culture, patient fibroblasts/induced pluripotent stem cells. <break/>Increased</td><td valign="top">Increased <italic>miR-431</italic> regulates motor neuron neurite length by targeting chondrolectin involved in motor neuron axon outgrowth.</td><td valign="top">(<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib136">Wertz et al., 2016</xref>)</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn><p><sup>1&#160;</sup><italic>miR-9</italic>/<italic>9*</italic> is another microRNA potentially implicated in motor neuron disease. It has been linked to the loss of spinal motor neurons that leads to SMA.</p><p><sup>2&#160;</sup>Since <italic>miR-206</italic> is required for efficient regeneration of neuromuscular synapses after acute nerve injury, this scenario probably accounts for its salutary effects in SMA.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap>