<table-wrap xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="table3" position="float"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.50848.008</object-id><label>Table 3.</label><caption><title>Proposed SMN-associated RNA-binding proteins involved in microRNA pathways.</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th valign="top">SMN-associated RBPs</th><th valign="top">RBP interaction assay</th><th valign="top">General functions in posttranscriptional regulation of mRNA</th><th valign="top">Proposed roles in miRNA metabolism/processing</th><th valign="top">Neuronal modeling mechanism</th><th valign="top">References</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td valign="top">TAR DNA-binding protein-43 <break/>(TDP-43)<sup>a,b</sup></td><td valign="top">FLAG-Drosha or FLAG-TDP-43 interacts in nuclear extracts from HEK293T cells. Partial colocalization of TDP-43 and SMN in MNs.</td><td valign="top">Transcriptional regulation, pre-mRNA splicing, mRNA transport and translation</td><td valign="top">1. Integrating with the Dicer and Drosha complexes <break/>2. Regulating pre-miRNA biogenesis</td><td valign="top">Neuron differentiation, neuronal plasticity, synapse formation, neurite outgrowth</td><td valign="top">(<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib65">Kawahara and Mieda-Sato, 2012</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib135">Wang et al., 2002</xref>)</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Fused sarcoma/translocated in liposarcoma (FUS/TLS)<sup>a,c</sup></td><td valign="top">IP and GST pulldown SMN in HeLa nuclear extracts and mouse neuroblastoma (N2a) using FUS antibody.</td><td valign="top">Transcriptional regulation, pre-mRNA splicing, mRNA transport and translation</td><td valign="top">Recruiting the Drosha complex</td><td valign="top">Synapse formation, neuronal plasticity, neurite outgrowth, neuronal differentiation and proliferation</td><td valign="top">(<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib95">Morlando et al., 2012</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib117">Sun et al., 2015</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib144">Yamazaki et al., 2012</xref>)</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Fragile X mental retardation protein (FMRP)</td><td valign="top">IP and GST pulldown SMN complex in human neuroblastoma SH-SY5Y cells using FLAG-tagged FMRP antibody. <break/>IP antibodies specific to human FMRP were used to pull down Dicer and associated miRNAs in an EBV-transformed human B cell line. IP was performed from total HeLa cell lysates with a monoclonal antibody to eIF2C2.</td><td valign="top">mRNA stability, translation inhibition</td><td valign="top">Integrating with AGO and Dicer in RNA-induced silencing complex (RISC)<sup>d</sup></td><td valign="top">Synapse formation, neuronal plasticity, neurite outgrowth, neuronal differentiation and proliferation</td><td valign="top">(<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib32">Edbauer et al., 2010</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib58">Jin et al., 2004</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib106">Piazzon et al., 2008</xref>)</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">KH-type splicing regulatory protein (KSRP)</td><td valign="top">Endogenous KSRP was IP from N2a cells with SMN Tudor domain. KSRP and SMN colocalize in neuronal processes foci</td><td valign="top">mRNA stability, translation inhibition</td><td valign="top">Interacting with Drosha and Dicer complexes to regulate miRNA maturation and mRNA decay</td><td valign="top">KSRP is expressed in the nervous system in both neurons and glia and plays a role in control of neuronal mRNA stability and rate of axonal outgrowth</td><td valign="top">(<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib4">Amirouche et al., 2014</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib119">Tadesse et al., 2008</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib124">Trabucchi et al., 2009</xref>)</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">HuD (ELAV-like protein 4)</td><td valign="top">SMN and the neuron-specific RBP HuD interact biochemically in cultured primary cortical neurons, MN1-cells, cultured mouse MNs, rat brain extracts. Genetic evidence from zebrafish embryos support that the interaction between SMN and HuD is critical for MN development.</td><td valign="top">mRNA stability, transport, translation, mTOR pathway</td><td valign="top">Interacting with RISC<sup>d</sup> to regulate miRNA function</td><td valign="top">Axon development, maintenance, and plasticity</td><td valign="top">(<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib40">Fukao et al., 2014</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib48">Hao le et al., 2017</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib84">Loffreda et al., 2015</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib114">Sosanya et al., 2013</xref>)</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">IMP1 (IGF2BP1; ZBP1), insulin-like growth factor 2 mRNA-binding protein 1</td><td valign="top">IP and GST pulldown SMN in brain lysates extracts using IMP1 antibody.</td><td valign="top">Promotes mRNA stability by preventing miRNA-mediated silencing</td><td valign="top">Interacting with AGO2 to regulate miRNA function</td><td valign="top">Axon development</td><td valign="top">(<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib37">Fallini et al., 2014</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib42">Gardiner et al., 2015</xref>) <break/>(<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib25">Degrauwe et al., 2016</xref>)</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn><p>a. TDP-43 and FUS/TLS proteins bind to pre-mRNA molecules and determine their fates by regulating splicing, transport, stability and translation.</p><p>b. The RNA-binding protein, TDP43, biochemically interacts with the miRNA processing enzyme Drosha, raising the possibility that TDP-43 may play a role in miRNA processing.</p></fn><fn><p>c. FUS/TLS promotes biogenesis of specific miRNAs, including <italic>miR-132</italic>, <italic>miR-134</italic>, and <italic>miR-9</italic>.</p><p>d. Additional proteins associated with RISC include MOV10 and Hu-AntigenR.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap>