<table-wrap xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="table2" position="float"><label>Table 2.</label><caption><title>Key elements of teaching and learning to include in an educational resource on the principles of rigorous research.</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th>Key element</th><th>Teaching and learning principle</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><italic>Clear learning objectives</italic></td><td>Define the learning objectives upfront, identify ways to measure achievement of these objectives, and then design activities to support learning (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib7">Bradforth et al., 2015</xref>).</td></tr><tr><td><italic>Inquiry-based learning</italic></td><td>Encourage students to pose their own questions, apply commonly used tools and methods to actively explore their questions, and provide evidence when explaining phenomena (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib7">Bradforth et al., 2015</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib16">Corwin et al., 2015</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib29">Minner et al., 2010</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib21">Handelsman et al., 2004</xref>).</td></tr><tr><td><italic>Relevance</italic></td><td>Provide feedback on real-world experiments, whether in the classroom or the laboratory, as a way to demonstrate relevance and stimulate interest. Opportunities for personalized application and discussion in the local setting with the help of a facilitator&#8217;s guide are particularly critical, as adults typically learn most effectively when given the opportunity for immediate personal utility and value (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib43">Walkington and Bernacki, 2018</xref>). Emphasize the ability to contribute to a larger purpose or gain social standing (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib45">Yeager et al., 2014</xref>).</td></tr><tr><td><italic>Individuality</italic></td><td>Include a range of approaches to teaching and learning to accommodate different levels of knowledge and skills, motivations, and senses of self-efficacy (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib43">Walkington and Bernacki, 2018</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib39">Raman, 2014</xref>).</td></tr><tr><td><italic>Self-efficacy</italic></td><td>Allow individuals to gain self-efficacy by experiencing a feeling of progress, being challenged in low-stakes environments, and working through confusing concepts successfully (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib20">D&#8217;Mello et al., 2014</xref>). This is more effective when the person feels psychologically safe to take risks and fail in front of their local scientific community.</td></tr><tr><td><italic>Belonging</italic></td><td>Facilitate learning, foster collaboration, and recognize diverse perspectives in order to encourage learners to gain agency and forge a connection with the intellectual community (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib4">Bjork et al., 2013</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib8">Brown and Adler, 2008</xref>).</td></tr><tr><td><italic>Recognition of complexity</italic></td><td>Include complexity and inconsistencies in training examples rather than simplification for the sake of a persuasive story (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib22">Howitt and Wilson, 2014</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib14">Coleman, 1987</xref>). This counteracts the drive to smooth over inconvenient but potentially important details and highlights the importance of confounding variables, potential artefactual influences, reproducibility, and robustness of the findings.</td></tr><tr><td><italic>Cultivation of growth</italic></td><td>Nurture positive behaviors, like acknowledging and learning from mistakes, rather than penalize imperfect practices (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib1">Alberts et al., 2015</xref>). Mentors at all career stages are encouraged to model these positive behaviors and to share their own failures, the drudgery and frustrations of science, and their approaches to coping emotionally and growing intellectually while maintaining rigorous research practices.</td></tr><tr><td><italic>Assessment of behavioral change</italic></td><td>Measure success via gains in learner competency and changes to their real-world approaches to research. Changes in laboratory practice could be assessed by user self-reports, by analysis of research presented at meetings (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib40">Silberberg et al., 2017</xref>) and in publications (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib27">MacLeod et al., 2015</xref>), or by querying scientists on whether discussions with their mentors and colleagues led to changes in laboratory and institutional culture. Collaborate from the beginning with individuals who specialize in assessment design in higher education settings (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib7">Bradforth et al., 2015</xref>).</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>