<table-wrap xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="inlinetable1" position="anchor"><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><tbody><tr><th colspan="4" valign="top">(A) General reporting details</th></tr><tr><th valign="top">What to report?</th><th valign="top">Why is this considered important?</th><th valign="top">What can go wrong or be ambiguous?</th><th valign="top"><bold>Recommendations on how to proceed</bold></th></tr><tr><td valign="top">Details on data recording and response quantification pipeline</td><td valign="top">&#8226; because differences in data recording and quantification (i.e., response scoring) can make a substantial difference</td><td valign="top"/><td valign="top">&#8226; report recording equipment and all settings used (e.g., filter) <break/>&#8226; report software used for response quantification <break/>&#8226; report precise details of response quantification</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Minimal response criterion (&#956;S) to define a valid SCR</td><td valign="top">&#8226; to define valid responses</td><td valign="top">&#8226; minimally detectable amplitude (e.g., 0.01, 0.02, 0.03, 0.05 &#181;S, etc.) may be sample- and equipment-specific <break/>&#8226; no clear recommendations (existing guidelines provide a range of 0.01 to 0.05 &#181;S) because&#160;this is influenced by noise level and equipment</td><td valign="top">&#8226; test different minimal response criteria in the data set and define the cutoff empirically. In our experience (Data set 1), a cutoff was easily determined empirically by visually inspecting responses at different cutoffs (e.g.,&#160;&lt;0.01 &#181;S, between 0.01 &#181;S and 0.02 &#181;S) and by&#160;evaluating their discrimination from noise</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Whether the first CS+ and/or the first CS&#8211; trial is&#160;included or not, and information on trial sequence</td><td valign="top">&#8226; no learning can be evident in the first trial, as the first US may occur at the earliest at the end of the CS+ and hence after the scoring window for the CS+-induced SCR <break/>&#8226; if the first trial is a CS&#8211;, no learning can have taken place as the US has not been presented yet <break/>&#8226; inclusion of the first trial (or the first trials in partial reinforcement protocols) may thus&#160;artificially reduce CS+/CS&#8211; discrimination</td><td valign="top">&#8226; in fully randomized partial reinforcement protocols, US presentations may cluster in the first or last half of the acquisition training, which will impact on CS+/CS&#8211;discrimination in SCRs</td><td valign="top">&#8226; careful experimental design with respect to trial-sequences (in particular in partial reinforcement protocols) <break/>&#8226; report whether&#160;the&#160;first trial for both CS+ and CS&#8211; is excluded because&#160;it may induce noise and bias CS+/CS&#8211; discrimination towards non-discrimination and as the first trial is sensitive to trial sequence effects</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Precise number of trials considered (if applicable for each trial type including reinforced and non-reinforced CS+ trials in case of partial reinforcement)</td><td valign="top">&#8226; often difficult/ambiguous to infer this information from the 'Materials&#160;and&#160;methods' section of a report<sup>a</sup> <break/>&#8226; number of trials that the &#8216;last half&#8217; or &#8216;full phase&#8217; refers to is contingent on experimental design and hence ambiguous and imprecise (see <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig2">Figure 2B</xref>)</td><td valign="top"/><td valign="top">&#8226; precision in reporting rather than relying on the reader making the right inferences <break/>&#8226; specify clearly the number of trials per stimulus type that are comprised in the &#8216;last half&#8217; or &#8216;full phase&#8217; <break/>&#8226; provide a justification (theoretical and/or empirical) for this decision<sup>b</sup></td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Details of&#160;whether&#160;results were based on raw or transformed data</td><td valign="top">&#8226; typically, transformations are required to allow&#160;interpretation&#160;of the reported results and to meet the assumptions of commonly statistical models</td><td valign="top"/><td valign="top">&#8226; report details of transformation (e.g., logarithmized [log/LN], range-corrected, square-root) including the number of trials considered (for each stimulus type) and the sequence of transformations applied and specific formula (e.g., for range-correction) <break/>&#8226; provide justification for any&#160;applied transformation (e.g., violation of assumption of normal distribution of residuals)</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Precise number of excluded participants and specific reasons</td><td valign="top">&#8226; often difficult/ambiguous to infer this information from the 'Materials&#160;and&#160;methods' section of a report<sup>a</sup></td><td valign="top">&#8226; different researchers have different opinions on what &#8216;exclusion&#8217; is (e.g., having individuals discontinue after a first experimental day based on performance should be considered and reported as exclusion)</td><td valign="top">&#8226; report a breakdown of specific reasons for exclusions with respective <italic>n</italic>&#8217;s</td></tr><tr><th colspan="4" valign="top">(B) Specific reporting details for exclusion of &#8216;non-learners&#8217;</th></tr><tr><th valign="top">What to report?</th><th valign="top">Why is this considered important?</th><th valign="top">What can go wrong or be ambiguous?</th><th valign="top">Recommendations on how to proceed</th></tr><tr><td valign="top">CS+/CS&#8211; discrimination is calculated on the basis of raw SCR or transformed (e.g., logarithmized [log/LN], range-corrected, square-root) scores</td><td valign="top">&#8226; the same criteria lead to different proportions of excluded individuals when applying them to raw or transformed data (see <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig3">Figure 3A and B</xref>)</td><td valign="top"/><td valign="top">&#8226; exact details of transformations (optimally calculation formulas) need to be included for full transparency and reproducibility</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Minimal differential (CS+ vs. CS) cutoff for &#8216;non-learning&#8217; in &#956;S</td><td valign="top">&#8226; different cutoffs lead to very different proportions of individuals excluded (see <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig3">Figure 3</xref>)</td><td valign="top"/><td valign="top">&#8226; exact details on cutoffs need to be included for full transparency and reproducibility</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">On what outcome measures is &#8216;non-learning&#8217; determined?</td><td valign="top">&#8226; &#8216;non-learners&#8217; do not necessarily converge across different outcome measures (Appendix 3, <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4s1">Figure 4&#8212;figure supplement 1</xref>)</td><td valign="top">&#8226; all outcome measures recorded need to be reported</td><td valign="top">&#8226; &#8216;non-learning&#8217; should not be based on a single outcome measure or a clear justification needs to be provided as&#160;to&#160;why a single measure is considered meaningful</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">If &#8216;non-learning&#8217; is determined by responding during fear acquisition training, which trial types and number of trials per trial type were considered?</td><td valign="top">&#8226; depending on the criteria employed, the same individual may be classified as &#8216;learner&#8217; or &#8216;non-learner&#8217; (see <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig4">Figure 4</xref>)</td><td valign="top"/><td valign="top">&#8226; classification as &#8216;non-learner&#8217; should be based on differential scores (CS+ vs. CS&#8211;), and the number of trials included for this calculation should be clearly justified. Providing a generally valid recommendation regarding the number of trials to be included is difficult&#160;because it critically depends on experimental design choices</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">If &#8216;non-learning &#8216;criteria are used, do they differ from criteria that&#160;the researcher or the research group used in previous publications? If yes, why were the criteria changed?</td><td valign="top">&#8226; provide explicit justifications on why different criteria were used previously and presently</td><td valign="top"/><td valign="top">&#8226; report differences between present and previous criteria used including references and justifications</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Did &#8216;non-learners&#8217; really&#160;fail&#160;to learn?</td><td valign="top">&#8226; important as a manipulation check but note that the absence of a statistically significant CS+/CS&#8211; discrimination effect in a group on average cannot be taken to imply that all individuals in this group do not show meaningful CS+/CS&#8211;discrimination</td><td valign="top">&#8226; individuals classified as &#8216;non-learners&#8217; may in fact show significant CS+/CS&#8211; discrimination in SCRs (see Appendix 2) or in other outcome measures (see <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig3s1">Figure 3&#8212;figure supplement 1</xref> and Appendix 4) and hence fail the manipulation check</td><td valign="top">&#8226; do the groups classified as &#8216;non-learners&#8217; and &#8216;learners&#8217; differ significantly in discrimination, and do &#8216;non-learners&#8217; really not discriminate in SCRs and other outcome measures? Report the data on this group graphically and/or statistically in the supplementary material (do not report the full sample with and without exclusions only)</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Are results contingent on the&#160;exclusion of &#8216;non-learners&#8217;?</td><td valign="top">&#8226; important to allow for transparency and to&#160;evaluate the impact of the results</td><td valign="top">&#8226; it is not clearly defined when results differ meaningfully when excluding and including &#8216;non-learners&#8217;</td><td valign="top">&#8226; provide results with and without exclusion of &#8216;non-learners&#8217; <break/>&#8226; additional analyses can be provided as supplementary material. When&#160;results are not contingent on the&#160;exclusion of &#8216;non-learners&#8217;, it is sufficient to mention this briefly in the results of the main manuscript (e.g., results are not contingent on the&#160;exclusion of &#8216;non-learners&#8217;) <break/>&#8226; if the&#160;results of the main analyses and hence the main conclusions change when &#8216;non-learners&#8217;&#160;are excluded,&#160;this needs to be included in the main manuscript ,&#160;and the implications need to be adequately discussed. Please note that this does not necessarily invalidate findings but can refine them</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Descriptive statistics for excluded &#8216;non-learners&#8217;</td><td valign="top">&#8226; important to allow for transparency and evaluation of the potential sample biases introduced</td><td valign="top"/><td valign="top">&#8226; report sex, age, anxiety levels, awareness</td></tr><tr><th colspan="4" valign="top">(C) Specific reporting details for exclusions of &#8216;non-responders&#8217;</th></tr><tr><th valign="top">What to report?</th><th valign="top">Why is this considered important?</th><th valign="top">What can go wrong or be ambiguous?</th><th valign="top">Recommendations on how to proceed</th></tr><tr><td valign="top">Whether &#8216;non-responses&#8217; are calculated on the basis of raw SCR or transformed (e.g., logarithmized [log/LN], range-corrected, square-root) scores</td><td valign="top">&#8226; the same criteria lead to different proportions of excluded individuals when applying to raw or transformed data (see <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig3">Figure 3A and B</xref>)</td><td valign="top"/><td valign="top">&#8226; exact details of transformations (optimally calculation formulas) need to be included for full transparency and reproducibility</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Minimal cutoff for &#8216;non-responses&#8217; in &#956;S</td><td valign="top">&#8226; it&#160;is&#160;often difficult/ambiguous to infer this information from the 'Materials&#160;and&#160;methods' section of a report<sup>a</sup> <break/>&#8226; higher cutoffs could unnecessarily reduce the sample size</td><td valign="top"/><td valign="top">&#8226; exact details on cutoffs need to be included for full transparency and reproducibility</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Was &#8216;non-responding&#8217; determined in a pre-experimental phase such as forced-breathing or US calibration?</td><td valign="top">&#8226; determining &#8216;non-responding&#8217; during a pre-experimental phase may help to detect malfunctioning of the equipment and allow&#160;this&#160;to be&#160;corrected prior to data acquisition <break/>&#8226; classification of &#8216;non-responders&#8217; independent of the experimental task and its specifications (e.g., number of US presentations)</td><td valign="top">&#8226; electrodes may detach between the pre-experimental phase and fear acquisition training</td><td valign="top">&#8226; report details of pre-experimental phase <break/>&#8226; classification in SCR &#8216;non-responders&#8217; should be based on a pre-experimental phase if no US presentations occur during the experiment, such as in case of threat of shock experiments, observational conditioning, extinction or return of fear tests</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">If &#8216;non-responding&#8217; is determined by responding during fear acquisition training, what trial types are considered?</td><td valign="top">&#8226; frequency of &#8216;non-responding&#8217; differs substantially between different stimuli (CS and US) but also between CS+ and CS&#8211; (see <xref ref-type="fig" rid="fig7">Figure 7A</xref>)</td><td valign="top">&#8226; &#8216;non-responding&#8217; to the US may be due to technical failure (i.e., no US was administered)</td><td valign="top">&#8226; classification in SCR &#8216;non-responders&#8217; should <bold>not</bold> be based on SCRS elicited by CS (CS+, CS&#8211; or both), but should be based on US responding <break/>&#8226; a question on the estimated number of US presented during fear acquisition training (and all other phases) may serve as a manipulation check</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Descriptive statistics for excluded &#8216;non-responder&#8217;</td><td valign="top">&#8226; important to allow for transparency and evaluation of the potential sample biases introduced</td><td valign="top"/><td valign="top">&#8226; report sex, age, anxiety levels, awareness</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn><p><sup>a</sup> based on our experience with extracting this information from literature identified in the systematic literature search reported in this manuscript.</p><p><sup>b&#160;</sup>&#8216;others have done this previously&#8217; is not an acceptable justification in our point of view.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap>