<table-wrap xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="tbl2" position="float"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.25069.008</object-id><label>Table 2.</label><caption><p>Coordinates of the ATL nodes, and the calculated values of the within module weighted degree and participation coefficient.</p><p><bold>DOI:</bold> <ext-link ext-link-type="doi" xlink:href="10.7554/eLife.25069.008">http://dx.doi.org/10.7554/eLife.25069.008</ext-link></p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th>Number Of Voxels</th><th>MNI center coordinates</th><th>Within module weighted degree</th><th>Participation coefficient</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>23</td><td>42, -14, -26</td><td>3.91</td><td>0.58</td></tr><tr><td>13</td><td>40, -10, -32</td><td>4.81</td><td>0.58</td></tr><tr><td>20</td><td>40, -12, -28</td><td>5.15</td><td>0.59</td></tr><tr><td><bold>Voxels</bold> </td><td rowspan="3">40, -10, -32</td><td><bold>Weighted&#160;Mean</bold>:</td><td><bold>Weighted Mean:</bold></td></tr><tr><td valign="top"><bold>Sum:</bold> </td><td valign="top"><break/></td><td valign="top"><break/></td></tr><tr><td>55</td><td>4.63</td><td>0.58</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn id="tblfn2"><p>Coordinates of the ATL are in line with (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib62">Rajimehr et al., 2009</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib61">Pyles et al., 2013</xref>). To assess whether the differences are specific to face-selective nodes, the ratio of face-selective nodes and non-face selective nodes connected to the ATL nodes was quantified using within-module weighted degree and participation coefficient. Within-module weighted degree measures the ISFC level of a node within its module. In this analysis, a module is defined as one of the three types of functional tags (faces, non-faces and overlap). Note that this definition is different from the graph theoretical modularity measure as used in the first section of the results. The participation coefficient measures the inter-module diversity of the nodes' connections, meaning how much a node is connected not only within its own module but across modules (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib35">Guimer&#224; and Nunes Amaral, 2005</xref>).</p></fn><fn id="tblfn3"><p>This resulted in a within-module weighted degree weighted average of 4.63 and a participation coefficient weighted average of 0.58. Values greater than 2 are considered as a 'module hub'. Additionally, 'module hubs' with a participation coefficient between 0.3 and 0.75 are treated as 'connector hubs', that is hubs with many connections to most of the other modules (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib35">Guimer&#224; and Nunes Amaral, 2005</xref>). Importantly, based on these standard values, the differences between controls and CPs, assigned to the ATL, are not a priori face specific.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap>