<table-wrap xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="inlinetable2" position="anchor"><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th valign="top">Control name</th><th valign="top">Algorithm used</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td valign="top">Trailing Edges</td><td valign="top">Removes trailing edges from the image. This uses a bespoke algorithm written by the author and uses the binary edge map as input. First, the image is scanned to locate edge pixels that have only one neighbour and adds these to a list. <break/>Then, for each point in the list; <break/>1. Remove the pixel from the target image <break/>2. Check the neighbourhood for connected pixels, if there is only one connected neighbour add it to the list. <break/>This has the effect of removing trailing edge fragments from the edge map image.</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Remove Small Objects</td><td valign="top">Removes pixel connected objects from the binary image that are smaller than a user selected threshold. User can choose from the set: <break/>{&#8216;10&#8217;,&#8216;20&#8217;,&#8216;30&#8217;,&#8216;40&#8217;,&#8216;50&#8217;,&#8216;100&#8217;,&#8216;150&#8217;,&#8216;200&#8217;,&#8216;250&#8217;,&#8216;300&#8217;,&#8216;350&#8217;, <break/>&#8216;400&#8217;,&#8216;450&#8217;,&#8216;500&#8217;} <break/>Objects smaller than the selected threshold will be removed from the image.</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Dilate</td><td valign="top">Standard binary image dilation algorithm</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Skeletonise</td><td valign="top">Skeletonises image by using an adaption of the algorithm proposed in <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib2">Arcelli et al. (1975)</xref>. The masks proposed in the paper are applied in (simulated) parallel fashion to image pixels until the resultant image reaches idempotence.</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Local Maxima for Edges</td><td valign="top">Alongside dilation and erosion, this operation is used to align the single pixel-wide edges to the junction on the original grey scale image (junction marker 1) more closely. It uses the original grey scale image and the single pixel-width edge map as inputs. The user is asked to select the neighbourhood size from the set: <break/>{&#8216;3&#8217;,&#8216;5&#8217;,&#8216;7&#8217;,&#8216;9&#8217;,&#8216;11&#8217;,&#8216;15&#8217;,&#8216;21&#8217;,&#8216;25&#8217;} <break/>For each pixel in the binary edge map that is set to a 1, the neighbourhood around that pixel is inspected in the original grey scale edge junction marker one image. The location of pixel with maximum grey scale value in the neighbourhood of inspected pixel in junction marker one image is set to a &#8216;1&#8217; in the resultant binary image. It can be performed on gradually reducing neighbourhood sizes.</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Edge Map Toggle</td><td valign="top">Rotates the background image that the binary edge map image is projected onto. <break/>Either shows just a binary image, the Junction one channel or the Junction two channel. This control will rotate through the options in turn.</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Add Straight Line</td><td valign="top">A tool to draw straight lines on the edge map image using the mouse. Select by clicking the appropriate radio button and then click left mouse button on the image at the line start point and click again with the left button at the line end point. The line will be displayed on the image. <break/>Multiple straight lines can be added by multiple mouse clicks that uses the last point as the line start point. Edges can be traced quickly using this feature. Turn off the tool by clicking the right mouse button and move to a different location.</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Remove Edge</td><td valign="top">A tool to erase parts of the edge map using the mouse. Select the appropriate radio button on the interface and move the mouse over the edge fragments that are to be removed.</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Reset</td><td valign="top">Returns to step 1 &#8216;Isolate edges&#8217;</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>