<table-wrap xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="table4" position="float"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.28811.023</object-id><label>Table 4.</label><caption><title>Generalised linear mixed effects models (GLMM) predicting the fertilisation success of male chinook salmon in sperm competition trials using two males and one female.</title><p>Trials were conducted using two seminal fluid (SF) treatments, either unmanipulated milt, or recombined ejaculates for which the sperm for both competitors were recombined with the seminal fluid of their rival. Sperm concentration was controlled so that the same number of sperm were used for each male. The first models used the social status of each male to predict the proportion of offspring sired (n&#160;=&#160;20). The second models used the relative sperm velocity (VAP, &#181;m s<sup>&#8722;1</sup>) between competitors to predict the difference in offspring sired (n&#160;=&#160;20). The final model shows that the change in relative sperm velocity between males within the same male-male-female combinations across SF treatments was a significant predictor of the change in the proportion of eggs sired by that male&#8217;s sperm across SF treatments (n&#160;=&#160;20). p-Values are calculated using Satterthwaite approximations to degrees of freedom and 95% confidence intervals were calculated using the Wald method. Significant values are highlighted in bold.</p><p><supplementary-material id="table4sdata1"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.28811.024</object-id><label>Table 4&#8212;source data 1.</label><caption><title>Source data for GLMM models predicting the fertilisation success of male chinook salmon in sperm competition trials.</title><p>This Excel file contains data on the proportion of eggs sired by each male and the social status of those males. The data is presented in two tabs, the first for the unmanipulated milt and the second for the recombined ejaculate seminal fluid treatments.</p></caption><media mime-subtype="xlsx" mimetype="application" xlink:href="elife-28811-table4-data1-v1.xlsx"/></supplementary-material></p><p><supplementary-material id="table4sdata2"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.28811.025</object-id><label>Table 4&#8212;source data 2.</label><caption><title>Source data for GLMM models predicting the fertilisation success of male chinook salmon in sperm competition trials.</title><p>This Excel file contains data on the diffence in the number of eggs sired between males in each sperm competition trial and the relative sperm velocity of those males.&#160;The data is presented in two tabs, the first for the unmanipulated milt and the second for the recombined ejaculate seminal fluid treatments.</p></caption><media mime-subtype="xlsx" mimetype="application" xlink:href="elife-28811-table4-data2-v1.xlsx"/></supplementary-material></p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th valign="top">Response variable</th><th valign="top">SF treatment</th><th valign="top">Parameters <break/>(fixed effects)</th><th valign="top">Estimate</th><th valign="top">95%</th><th valign="top">P value</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td rowspan="2" valign="top">Proportion of offspring sired</td><td valign="top">Unmanipulated</td><td valign="top">Intercept <break/>Social status</td><td valign="top">&#8722;0.38 <break/>1.11</td><td valign="top">0.63&#8211;1.58</td><td valign="top"><bold>&lt;0.0001</bold></td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Recombined</td><td valign="top">Intercept <break/>SF social status</td><td valign="top">&#8722;3.24 <break/>6.23</td><td valign="top">4.7&#8211;7.7</td><td valign="top"><bold>&lt;0.0001</bold></td></tr><tr><td rowspan="2" valign="top">Difference in number of offspring sired between males</td><td valign="top">Unmanipulated</td><td valign="top">Intercept <break/>Relative sperm velocity</td><td valign="top">&#8722;1.49e<sup>03</sup> <break/>1.44e<sup>&#8722;01</sup></td><td valign="top">0.06&#8211;0.23</td><td valign="top"> <bold>0.003</bold></td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Recombined</td><td valign="top">Intercept <break/>Relative sperm velocity</td><td valign="top">3.72e<sup>03</sup> <break/>0.13</td><td valign="top">0.05&#8211;0.21</td><td valign="top"> <bold>0.003</bold></td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Difference in proportion of eggs sired across SF treatments</td><td valign="top">NA</td><td valign="top">Intercept <break/>Difference in relative sperm velocity across SF treatments</td><td valign="top">&#8722;56.39 <break/>0.006</td><td valign="top">3.5e<sup>&#8722;03</sup>&#8211; 7.6e<sup>&#8722;03</sup></td><td valign="top"> <bold>0.0001</bold></td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>