<table-wrap xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="tbl4" position="float"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.05604.031</object-id><label>Table 4.</label><caption><p>PCA comparison of GSL profiles produced by GSL genotypes from synthetic laboratory population grown in the chamber and all three environments</p><p><bold>DOI:</bold> <ext-link ext-link-type="doi" xlink:href="10.7554/eLife.05604.031">http://dx.doi.org/10.7554/eLife.05604.031</ext-link></p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th rowspan="2">Environment</th><th colspan="2">PCA1 = 48.5%</th><th colspan="2">PCA2 = 29%</th><th colspan="2">PCA3 = 16%</th><th colspan="2">PCA4 = 6%</th></tr><tr><th>R</th><th>p value</th><th>R</th><th>p value</th><th>R</th><th>p value</th><th>R</th><th>p value</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Chamber</td><td>1.00</td><td/><td>1.00</td><td/><td>1.00</td><td/><td>1.00</td><td/></tr><tr><td>UCD2012</td><td>0.97</td><td>&lt;0.001</td><td>0.97</td><td>&lt;0.001</td><td>0.82</td><td>&lt;0.001</td><td>0.96</td><td>&lt;0.001</td></tr><tr><td>UWY2011</td><td>0.91</td><td>&lt;0.001</td><td>0.95</td><td>&lt;0.001</td><td>0.74</td><td>&lt;0.001</td><td>0.97</td><td>&lt;0.001</td></tr><tr><td>UWY2012</td><td>0.90</td><td>&lt;0.001</td><td>0.91</td><td>&lt;0.001</td><td>0.85</td><td>&lt;0.001</td><td>0.86</td><td>&lt;0.001</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn><p>Glucosinolate analysis was conducted on the 17 genotypes within a Long-day growth chamber (16 hr light) set to match the median light regime for the three environmments. Principal component analysis was conducted on the mean glucosinolate accumulation for the aliphatic glucosinoles within the chamber environment. This creates a set of mathematical descriptors of the chemotype variation across the 17 genotypes. The first three eigenvectors were used to generate scores from the lsmeans of the glucosinolates across the 17 glucosinolate genotypes independently for the chamber and three different field environments values. These scores were then correlated to test if the GSL profiles were similar or not across the environments. The R of the correlation to the Chamber scores for the 17 genotypes for each of the three PCA vectors are shown in conjunction with the p value as determined by Pearson correlation. To the right of each PCA vector label is shown the fraction of total variance approximated by the given vector. In total, the four vectors describe &gt;99% of the GSL profile variance.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap>