<table-wrap xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="inlinetable5" position="anchor"><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th valign="top">Control name</th><th valign="top">Algorithm used</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td valign="top">Corner Detection</td><td valign="top">The algorithm used is based on the Douglas Peucker method defined in <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib37">Poiker and Douglas (2011)</xref>. The user sets the epsilon value required using a slider and the corners appear in the image as defined by the algorithm. Raising the epsilon value decreases the number of corners that the algorithm adds to the image. Corners can also be manually added (left mouse click on cell edge) or removed (right mouse click on corner) from the image.</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Number of Dilations applied to Edge</td><td valign="top">This refers to the number of standard binary image dilations <break/>applied to the single pixel cell edge and creates the area will be measured. The area measured for the &#8216;junction marker 1&#8217; and &#8216;junction marker 2&#8217; by Junction Mapper can be altered using a slider control, the default value being 2.</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Junction marker 1 Threshold</td><td valign="top">A global threshold applied to the &#8216;junction marker 1&#8217; image over which pixels will be considered for inclusion in the resultant parameter calculations.</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Measurement Threshold</td><td valign="top">A global threshold applied to the Junction two channel over which pixels will be considered for inclusion in the resultant parameter calculations.</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Switch Background</td><td valign="top">There are three options: (i) just an edge map projected on to the &#8216;junction marker 1&#8217; image, (ii) the edge map projected onto the Junction two channel or (iii) the edge map plus the &#8216;junction marker 1&#8217; measurement area (the dilated edge) projected onto the &#8216;junction marker 1&#8217; channel. Using this control will rotate through the options in turn.</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Measure</td><td valign="top">This button will perform the cell boundary measurements detailed elsewhere. Note that this operation does not save the measurements.</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Return</td><td valign="top">Returns to step 5 &#8216;Measure each cell&#8217;</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>