<table-wrap xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="tbl2" position="float"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.06513.023</object-id><label>Author response table 1.</label><caption><p>Factors that challenge use of non-behavioral measures during emergence</p><p><bold>DOI:</bold> <ext-link ext-link-type="doi" xlink:href="10.7554/eLife.06513.023">http://dx.doi.org/10.7554/eLife.06513.023</ext-link></p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><tbody><tr><td><p><bold>Influencing factors</bold></p></td><td><p><bold>Reason</bold></p></td><td><p><bold>Relation to our study</bold></p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Amount of painful stimulation from surgery affecting respiration &amp; heart rate change</p></td><td><p>Variability in degree of suppression from nociceptive afferent drive by:</p><p>&#8226; Local or regional anesthesia (e.g. field blocks for hernia repairs, or penile blocks for hypospadias repair)</p><p>&#8226; Opioid dosing (dose and time course)</p></td><td><p><xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SD1-data">Supplementary File 1</xref> provides details on the individual infant clinical data.</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Control of respiratory function</p></td><td><p>&#8226; Variability in tidal volume and rate delivered via mechanical ventilation during anesthesia according to individual anesthesiologist&#8217;s clinical decisions. Resulting pCO2 influences ventilatory drive during emergence.</p><p>&#8226; Variability in anesthesiologist&#8217;s method to convert from controlled to assisted or spontaneous ventilation</p></td><td><p>Information unavailable.</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Pharmacologic effects on heart rate</p></td><td><p>Variability in use of neuromuscular blockade and need for reversal of neuromuscular blockade (case-dependent):</p><p>&#8226; Reversal of NM blockade requires cholinesterase inhibitors (e.g. neostigmine), which produce bradycardia, and muscarinic antagonists (i.e. atropine or glycopyrrolate), which produce tachycardia. Heart rate during emergence can reflect individual differences in responses to these, along with other contributors to sympathetic and parasympathetic heart rate modulation.</p><p>&#8226; Variability in timing of NM block reversal drug administration at the end of surgery, and effects on heart rate</p></td><td><p><xref ref-type="supplementary-material" rid="SD1-data">Supplementary File 1</xref> provides details on the individual infant clinical data.</p></td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>