<table-wrap xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="inlinetable4" position="anchor"><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><tbody><tr><td valign="top">Reference</td><td valign="top">Cell Type</td><td valign="top">Description of Activity</td><td valign="top">Timing</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Okubo et al. 2015</td><td valign="top">Putative HVC projection neurons: N= 285; 137/285 bout onset neurons; 98/285 bout offset neurons; 50/285 active both before and after bouts. 1 identified HVC-RA neuron firing at the end of bouts. At least 3 identified HVC-X neurons (2 bout onset, 1 bout offset).</td><td valign="top">Significant pre and post-bout activity in the 300ms window before and after bouts. Both pre and post-bout peaks occurred between 0 to 100 ms before or after bout onset or offset, respectively.</td><td valign="top">Activity hundreds of milliseconds before or after song vocalizations in mixed populations of neurons.</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Kao et al., 2008</td><td valign="top">LMAN neurons: N= 18; elevated activity before undirected song onset. N=16; decreased activity following cessation of undirected song.</td><td valign="top">In 18 neurons, &#8220;firing rate in a 500ms interval from 600 to 100ms before undirected song was greater than the average spontaneous firing rate&#8221;. In 16 neurons, firing rate &#8220;was lower than the average level of spontaneous activity&#8221; following song offset.</td><td valign="top">Activity in LMAN neurons hundreds of milliseconds before or after song vocalization, but only in undirected social context.</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Goldberg et al., 2010</td><td valign="top">Area X-DLM neurons (HF-2 neurons): N=37 neurons</td><td valign="top">In HF-2 neurons, &#8220;firing rate gradually increased before singing (0.56 &#177; 0.22s), and slowly returned to baseline following singing (1.64 &#177; 1.2s).&#8221;</td><td valign="top">Activity in AreaX-DLM neurons exhibited pre-song activity hundreds of milliseconds before song onset, and seconds after song offset.</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Day et al., 2009</td><td valign="top">Multiunit activity in HVC</td><td valign="top">Elevated activity in juvenile birds before and after song vocalization.</td><td valign="top">Unclear</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Rajan and Doupe, 2013</td><td valign="top">HVC-X neurons: N= 30; 12 antidromically identified, 18 putative. <break/>Putative Interneurons: N= 16</td><td valign="top">Activity of putative interneurons and HVC-X neurons shown to be correlated with onset times of introductory notes.</td><td valign="top">Activity time-locked to introductory note vocalization.</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Vyssotski et al. 2016</td><td valign="top">NIF neurons projecting to HVC</td><td valign="top">16 Nif-HVC neurons fire on average above baseline levels 70 ms prior to song onset and it decays to baseline about 30 ms prior to song offset.</td><td valign="top">Activity is time locked to introductory note type. Authors did not look beyond 500 or 1000 ms before song onset.</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Rajan 2018</td><td valign="top">HVC-X neurons: N=39; 13 antidromically identified, 26 putative. <break/>Putative interneurons: N=17</td><td valign="top">4 HVC-X neurons increased their activity (-928 ms to -129ms prior to song bout onset). 3 HVC-X neurons decreased activity -528ms to -47ms). 13 interneurons increased activity (~-674ms to -117ms).</td><td valign="top">Activity before any vocalization including introductory notes.</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>