<table-wrap xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="table1" position="float"><label>Table 1.</label><caption><title>The most common stocks and strains of the laboratory rat.</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th>Name</th><th>Inbred/ <break/>outbred*</th><th>Coat color</th><th>Origine</th><th>Use and characteristics</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Wistar</td><td>outbred</td><td>albino</td><td valign="top">The Wistar Institute, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, USA (1906)</td><td valign="top">The most-popular general multi-purpose models. Studies of infectious diseases, aging and as a surgical model.</td></tr><tr><td>Wistar Han</td><td>outbred</td><td>albino</td><td valign="top">Zentralinstitute f&#252;r Versuchstierzucht, Hannover, Germany</td><td valign="top">A general multi-purpose model, popular in preclinical safety assessments, and as an aging, oncological and surgical model.</td></tr><tr><td>Wistar Kyoto</td><td>outbred</td><td>albino</td><td valign="top">the Kyoto School of Medicine, Japan</td><td valign="top">Normotensive controls for the spontaneous hypertensive line, a depression and autism model.</td></tr><tr><td>Sprague Dawley</td><td>outbred</td><td>albino</td><td valign="top">The Sprague-Dawley farms, Madison, Wisconsin, USA (1925). Derived from a hybrid Hooded male and a female Wistar.</td><td valign="top">Behavioral studies and as models in obesity, oncology and surgical research.</td></tr><tr><td>Long Evans</td><td>outbred</td><td>hooded</td><td valign="top">The University of California, USA. Created by Herbert McClean Evans and Joseph Abraham Long (1915&#8211;1922). A result of crossbreeding albino females and wild males caught near the University.</td><td valign="top">Behavioral studies. Known for their docility and ease of breeding but prone to spontaneous seizures.</td></tr><tr><td>Brown Norway</td><td>inbred</td><td>pigmented</td><td valign="top">Derived from a pen-bred colony of wild-caught rats maintained by King and Aptekman at the Wistar Institute in the 1930s. The strain was created by Silvers and Billingham in 1958 (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib43">Hedrich, 2000</xref>).</td><td valign="top">Immunological and transplantation studies. Selected as the sequencing target in <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib40">Gibbs et al. (2004)</xref>.</td></tr><tr><td>Lewis</td><td>inbred</td><td>albino</td><td valign="top">Developed by Margaret Lewis from the Wistar rats in the early 1950s</td><td valign="top">Enhanced susceptibility to many experimental inflammatory conditions, such as PGPS-induced arthritis, adjuvant-induced arthritis, collagen-induced arthritis, autoimmune encephalitis, autoimmune thyroiditis and enterocolitis (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib114">Zhang, 2010</xref>). Characterized by their docile behavior but relatively low fertility.</td></tr><tr><td>Zucker fatty rats</td><td>outbred</td><td>hooded</td><td valign="top">Developed by crossing the Sherman strain with the Meck stock 13M strain (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib52">Kava et al., 1990</xref>)</td><td valign="top">Most often used as a model of genetic obesity. Relatively insensitive to leptin due to a mutation in the long form of the leptin receptor (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib110">van der Spek et al., 2012</xref>). Characterized by hyperlipidemia, hypercholesterolemia and hyperinsulinemia (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib52">Kava et al., 1990</xref>).</td></tr><tr><td>Nude rats</td><td>inbred</td><td>albino hooded grey</td><td valign="top">The nude mutation first encountered in 1953 in an outbred colony of hooded rats at the Rowett Research Institute in Aberdeen, Scotland. The mutation reappeared independently in Aberdeen in 1977 and in New Zealand in 1979 (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib42">Hanes, 2006</xref>). Since than numerous new strains have been developed. For instance, a spontaneous mutation model isolated from a Crl:CD(SD) colony in Charles River in the late 1980s.</td><td valign="top">Characterized by almost complete absence of fur. Experimental models for a variety of immunological, surgical, infectious, transplant-related and oncological procedures. Uniquely capable of maintaining increased tumours without visible distress and enlarged body weight (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib42">Hanes, 2006</xref>). Also useful in wound healing and dermatology.</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn><p><sup>*</sup>Inbred rat strains are created by brother-sister or parent-offspring mating for at least 20 generations. It produces almost genetically identical individuals (after 20 generations rats are homozygous at 98.7% of all alleles and the residual heterozygosity decreases as inbreeding continue; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib63">Lohmiller and Swing, 2006</xref>). Outbred rat stocks are developed from large colonies with males and females selected randomly from different breeding groups; stock animals are genetically different, which can represent inter-individual differences occurring in natural environment (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib63">Lohmiller and Swing, 2006</xref>; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib74">Olson and Graham, 2014</xref>).</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap>