<table-wrap xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="resptable1" position="float"><label>Author response table 1.</label><caption><title>Detailed conclusions of the cell line authentication.</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th>Sample name</th><th>Organism</th><th>Conclusion</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td valign="top">A549</td><td valign="top">Human</td><td valign="top">According to our analysis of the submitted sample there is no detectable contamination with human origin. <break/>The analyzed data of the submitted sample match 100% to the DNA profile of the cell line A549 (ATCC CRM-CCL<sup>-</sup>185TM) and 100% over all 15 autosomal STRs to Microsynth&#8217;s reference DNA profile of A549 (Mic_150733).</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">Calu-6</td><td valign="top">Human</td><td valign="top">According to our analysis of the submitted sample there is no detectable contamination with human origin. <break/>The analyzed data of the submitted sample match 100% to the DNA profile of the cell line Calu-6 (ATCC HTB-56TM) and 100% over all 15 autosomal STRs to the DNA profile of Calu-6 (Cellosaurus, RRID:CVCL_0236).</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">H460</td><td valign="top">Human</td><td valign="top">According to our analysis of the submitted sample there is no detectable contamination with human origin. <break/>The analyzed data of the submitted sample match 100% to the DNA profile of the cell line NCI-H460 [H460] (ATCC HTB-177TM) and 100% over all 15 autosomal STRs to the DNA profile of NCI-H460 (Cellosaurus, RRID:CVCL_0459).</td></tr><tr><td valign="top">SW 1573</td><td valign="top">Human</td><td valign="top">According to our analysis of the submitted sample there is no detectable contamination with human origin. <break/>The analyzed data of the submitted sample match 93.3% to the DNA profile of the cell line SW 1573 [SW-1573, SW1573] (ATCC CRL-2170TM) and 93.1% over all 15 autosomal STRs to the DNA profile of SW 1573 (Cellosaurus, RRID:CVCL_1720). <break/>Cell line samples matching at &#8805; 80% of alleles across the eight core reference loci are said to be related.</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>