<table-wrap xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="tbl1" position="float"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.04585.006</object-id><label>Table 1.</label><caption><p>Regions of interest from which BOLD time series were extracted</p><p><bold>DOI:</bold> <ext-link ext-link-type="doi" xlink:href="10.7554/eLife.04585.006">http://dx.doi.org/10.7554/eLife.04585.006</ext-link></p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th>ROIs in MNI standard space</th><th align="center">x</th><th align="center">y</th><th align="center">z</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Left M1</td><td align="center">&#8722;36</td><td align="center">&#8722;24</td><td align="center">62</td></tr><tr><td>Left PMv</td><td align="center">&#8722;58</td><td align="center">4</td><td align="center">30</td></tr><tr><td>Left PMd</td><td align="center">&#8722;22</td><td align="center">&#8722;4</td><td align="center">58</td></tr><tr><td>Left AIP</td><td align="center">&#8722;44</td><td align="center">&#8722;42</td><td align="center">46</td></tr><tr><td>Left pSPL</td><td align="center">&#8722;22</td><td align="center">&#8722;64</td><td align="center">54</td></tr><tr><td>Left V3A</td><td align="center">&#8722;26</td><td align="center">&#8722;86</td><td align="center">18</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn><p>6 mm diameter masks were created in Montreal Neurological Institute (MNI) space. Coordinates refer to MNI152_standard brain as provided by FSL. The ROI mask for M1 was based upon the meta-analysis of functional brain imaging data of motor control (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib49">Mayka et al., 2006</xref>). The PMv ROI location was then identified by finding the region in which BOLD activity was significantly correlated with activity in M1 at the group level, both during rest and during the grasping task. The peak resulting MNI coordinate [&#8722;58 4 30] was located in what is defined as PMv by <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib49">Mayka et al. (2006)</xref> which had a centre-of-mass at [&#8722;52 4 24]; more specifically, it lies in the 6v/F5c subdivision of PMv identified by <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib52">Neubert et al. (2014)</xref>. The ROI masks for AIP, PMd, pSPL, and V3A were the same size, but were centred on the group peak activation average coordinates of an fMRI study that employed a similar visually guided grasping task and the same apparatus (<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib31">Grol et al., 2007</xref>). Masks were registered to individual EPI space in a two-step process: the mask was transformed into individual, high-resolution structural space via non-linear registration (FSL FNIRT) and then into individual functional space via affine registration (FSL FLIRT; <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib38">Jenkinson et al., 2002</xref>).</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap>