<table-wrap xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="tbl2" position="float"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.09418.017</object-id><label>Table 2.</label><caption><p>The onset times in time-direction maps. The first main column shows the onset time calculated from trials aligned on target onset and the second main column shows the onset time calculated from trials aligned on saccade onset. Within each main column, the first minor column shows the time when the neural activity was significantly different from background activity (-20&#160;to&#160;0 before target onset). The second minor column shows the time when the neural activity represented the choice. In no-choice trials, this corresponds to the time when the activity of neurons with a preferred direction within &#177; 30&#176; of the target was significantly different from the activity of neurons where no target was presented (the neurons with preferred direction within 240&#8211;300&#176;). For choice trial, it corresponds to the time when the activity for the chosen target was significant different form the activity for the non-chosen target (in both cases the neurons with preferred direction within &#177; 30&#176; of their respective target). A permutation test with multiple comparison correction was used to calculate the onset times.</p><p><bold>DOI:</bold> <ext-link ext-link-type="doi" xlink:href="10.7554/eLife.09418.017">http://dx.doi.org/10.7554/eLife.09418.017</ext-link></p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th rowspan="2"/><th colspan="2">Time from target onset</th><th colspan="2">Time from saccade onset</th></tr><tr><th>Activity vs background</th><th>Chosen vs non-chosen</th><th>Activity vs background</th><th>Chosen vs non-chosen</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>No-choice</td><td>44&#160;ms</td><td/><td>-141&#160;ms</td><td/></tr><tr><td>Choice</td><td>40&#160;ms</td><td>105&#160;ms</td><td>-185&#160;ms</td><td>-70&#160;ms</td></tr><tr><td>Choice (dV&gt;=0.4)</td><td>44&#160;ms</td><td>92&#160;ms</td><td>-129&#160;ms</td><td>-68&#160;ms</td></tr><tr><td>Choice (dV&lt;0.4)</td><td>41&#160;ms</td><td>139&#160;ms</td><td>-169&#160;ms</td><td>-42&#160;ms</td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>