<table-wrap xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="tbl1" position="float"><label>Table 1.</label><caption><p>The first four <italic>eLife</italic>-sponsored presentations by early career researchers</p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><tbody><tr><td><bold>Rosanna A Alegado</bold> University of California, Berkeley, United States; Present address: University of Hawai`i at M&#227;noa</td><td>Alegado RA, Brown LW, Cao S, Dermenjian RK, Zuzow R, Fairclough SR, Clardy J, King N. 2012. A bacterial sulfonolipid triggers multicellular development in the closest living relatives of animals. <italic>eLife</italic> <bold>1</bold>:e00013. doi: <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://dx.doi.org/10.7554/eLife.00013">10.7554/eLife.00013</ext-link>.</td></tr><tr><td><bold>Jesse D Bloom</bold> Fred Hutchinson Cancer Research Center, Seattle, United States</td><td>Gong LI, Suchard MA, Bloom JD. 2013. Stability-mediated epistasis constrains the evolution of an influenza protein. <italic>eLife</italic> <bold>2</bold>:e00631. doi: <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://dx.doi.org/10.7554/eLife.00631">10.7554/eLife.00631</ext-link>.</td></tr><tr><td><bold>Israel S Fernandez</bold> Medical Research Council Laboratory of Molecular Biology, Cambridge, United Kingdom</td><td>Bai X, Fernandez I, McMullan G, Scheres SHW. 2013. Ribosome structures to near-atomic resolution from thirty thousand cryo-EM particles. <italic>eLife</italic> <bold>2</bold>:e00461. doi: <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://dx.doi.org/10.7554/eLife.00461">10.7554/eLife.00461</ext-link>.</td></tr><tr><td><bold>Wenhui Li</bold> National Institute of Biological Sciences, Beijing, China</td><td>Yan H, Zhong G, Xu G, He W, Jing Z, Gao Z, Huang Y, Qi Y, Peng B, Wang H, Fu L, Song M, Chen P, Gao W, Ren B, Sun Y, Cai T, Feng X, Sui J, Li W. 2012. Sodium taurocholate cotransporting polypeptide is a functional receptor for human hepatitis B and D virus. <italic>eLife</italic> <bold>1</bold>:e00049. doi: <ext-link ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://dx.doi.org/10.7554/eLife.00049">10.7554/eLife.00049</ext-link>.</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn><p>The editorial leadership of <italic>eLife</italic> has identified four particularly outstanding Research Articles that were published in the journal before the end of May 2013, and one early career author from each article has been invited to give a presentation at a meeting organized by one of the agencies that sponsor <italic>eLife</italic>. Another four authors will be invited to give presentations early next year.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap>