<table-wrap xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="app1table5" position="float"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.37385.019</object-id><label>Appendix 1&#8212;table 5.</label><caption><title>Data descriptions for the unpublished data analysed in the meta-analysis.</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th>Study ID*</th><th valign="top">Data description</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>14</td><td valign="top">88 individuals were separated into four captive mixed-sex groups. Live observations after mild food&#160;deprivation were conducted to record agonistic dyadic interactions (i.e. fights) over (mostly) food for around one week in Feb 2003 (total&#160;=&#160;1,563 fights). Bib length and width were measured for each male before the dominance observations using a ruler. More information can be found in <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib55">Lendvai et al., 2004</xref> and <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib8">B&#243;kony et al., 2012</xref>.</td></tr><tr><td>15</td><td valign="top">61 individuals were separated into three captive mixed-sex groups. Live observations after mild food&#160;deprivation were conducted to record agonistic dyadic interactions (i.e. fights) over (mostly) food between Oct and Dec 2005 (two groups) and 2006 (one group; total&#160;=&#160;2,003 fights). Bib area was measured for each male using standardized pictures taken after the dominance observations. More information can be found in <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib103">T&#243;th et al., 2009</xref> and <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib8">B&#243;kony et al., 2012</xref>.</td></tr><tr><td>16</td><td valign="top">60 individuals were separated into four captive mixed-sex groups. Live and video observations after mild&#160;food deprivation were conducted to record agonistic dyadic interactions (i.e. fights) over (mostly) food for around two weeks per group between Oct 2007 and Feb 2008 (total&#160;=&#160;6,641 fights). Bib length and width were measured for each male before the dominance observations using a ruler. More information can be found in <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib7">B&#243;kony et al., 2010</xref> and <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib8">B&#243;kony et al., 2012</xref>.</td></tr><tr><td>17</td><td valign="top">96 males were separated into four captive male-only groups. Videos after mild food&#160;deprivation were taken to record agonistic dyadic interactions (i.e. fights) over food for 10 days between Oct and Dec 2014 (total&#160;=&#160;3,776 fights). Bib area was measured several times for each male (median&#160;=&#160;3 times/male, range&#160;=&#160;2 to 6) using standardized pictures taken from Oct to Dec 2014, and the mean bib area of each individual was used in the analyses.</td></tr><tr><td>18</td><td valign="top">453 individuals (215 females and 238 males) were observed in seven discrete sampling events in a wild population of house sparrows at Lundy Island, UK. Videos were taken to record agonistic dyadic interactions (i.e. fights) over food for 20 days between Nov 2013 and Dec 2016 (total&#160;=&#160;11,063 fights). Bib length was measured several times for each male (median&#160;=&#160;1 time/male, range&#160;=&#160;1 to 6) from Nov 2013 to Dec 2016 using a calliper, and the mean bib area of each individual in each sampling event was used in the analyses.</td></tr><tr><td>19</td><td valign="top">128 individuals were separated into 16 captive mixed-sex groups. Live observations after mild food&#160;deprivation were conducted to record agonistic dyadic interactions (i.e. supplants and hold-offs) over food between Mar and Apr 2005 (total&#160;=&#160;5,496 fights). Bib length and width were measured for each male before the dominance observations using a calliper as in <xref ref-type="bibr" rid="bib65">Morrison et al., 2008</xref>.</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn><p>*Study ID corresponding to <xref ref-type="table" rid="table1">Table 1</xref> in main text.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap>