<table-wrap xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" id="table3" position="float"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.39856.024</object-id><label>Table 3.</label><caption><title>Polygenic scores for lifespan associate with out-of-sample parent and subject lifespans.</title><p>A&#160;polygenic risk score&#160;(PRS) was made for each subject using GWAS results that did not include the subject sets under consideration.&#160;Subject or parent survival information (age entry, age exit, age of death, if applicable) was used to test the association between polygenic risk score and survival as (a) a continuous score and (b) by dichotomising the top and bottom decile scores. Population &#8211; Population sample of test dataset, where E and W is England and Wales; Kin &#8211; Individuals tested for association with polygenic score; N &#8211; Number of lives used for analysis; Deaths &#8211; Number of deaths; Beta &#8211; Effect size per PRS standard deviation, in log<sub>e</sub>(protection ratio), doubled in parents to reflect the expected effect in cohort subjects. SE &#8211; Standard error, doubled in parents to reflect the expected error in cohort subjects; Years &#8211; Estimated years of life gained per PRS standard deviation; P &#8211; P value of two-sided test of association; Contrast age at death &#8211; difference between the median lifespan of individuals in the top and bottom deciles of the score in year of life (observed parent contrast is again doubled to account for imputation of their genotypes).</p><p><supplementary-material id="table3sdata1"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7554/eLife.39856.025</object-id><label>Table 3&#8212;source data 1.</label><caption><title>Polygenic survival scores in independent samples are most associated when including all markers.</title><p>A&#160;polygenic risk score&#160;was made for each subject using GWAS results that did not include the subject sets under consideration.&#160;Parent survival information (age and alive/dead status) was used to test the association between survival and several polygenic risk scores with different P value thresholds. Sample &#8211; Out-of-sample subsets of UK Biobank individuals used for PGRS association. N &#8211; Number of reported parental lifespans by sample individuals. Deaths &#8211; Number of reported parental deaths by sample individuals. Threshold &#8211; Criteria for SNPs to be included in the polygenic score. Beta &#8211; Log<sub>e</sub>(protection ratio) per standard deviation of polygenic score, doubled to reflect the effect of the score on offspring survival. SE &#8211; standard error of the effect estimate. Mean Years &#8211; Mean years of life gained per standard deviation in PGRS. P &#8211; P value of the effect of the polygenic score on lifespan.</p></caption><media mime-subtype="xlsx" mimetype="application" xlink:href="elife-39856-table3-data1-v2.xlsx"/></supplementary-material></p></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th colspan="4" valign="bottom">Sample descriptives</th><th colspan="4" valign="bottom">Effect of polygenic score</th><th colspan="2" valign="bottom">Contrast age at death</th></tr><tr><th>Population</th><th>Kin</th><th>N</th><th>Deaths</th><th>Beta</th><th>SE</th><th>Years</th><th>P</th><th>Men</th><th>Women</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Scotland</td><td>Parents</td><td>46,936</td><td>33,196</td><td>0.107</td><td>0.011</td><td>1.07</td><td>4.2E-22</td><td>5.6</td><td>5.6</td></tr><tr><td>Scotland</td><td>Subjects</td><td>24,059</td><td>941</td><td>0.085</td><td>0.033</td><td>0.85</td><td>1.0E-02</td><td>-</td><td>-</td></tr><tr><td>E and W</td><td>Parents</td><td>58,070</td><td>39,347</td><td>0.133</td><td>0.010</td><td>1.33</td><td>7.3E-39</td><td>6.4</td><td>4.8</td></tr><tr><td>E and W</td><td>Subjects</td><td>29,815</td><td>760</td><td>0.098</td><td>0.037</td><td>0.98</td><td>7.1E-03</td><td>-</td><td>-</td></tr><tr><td>Estonia</td><td>Parents</td><td>61,728</td><td>29,660</td><td>0.099</td><td>0.012</td><td>0.99</td><td>2.5E-17</td><td>3.0</td><td>2.8</td></tr><tr><td>Estonia</td><td>Subjects</td><td>24,800</td><td>2894</td><td>0.087</td><td>0.019</td><td>0.87</td><td>2.6E-06</td><td>3.5</td><td>2.7</td></tr><tr><td colspan="4" valign="bottom"/><td colspan="4" valign="bottom"><bold>Per standard deviation</bold></td><td colspan="2" valign="bottom"><bold>Top vs. bottom 10%</bold></td></tr></tbody></table></table-wrap>